music
音楽
Our protagonist today Qiu Wenda Director Qiu
今日の主役 チウ・ウェンダ チウ監督
and ladies and gentlemen
そして紳士淑女の皆様
And colleagues in our hospital
そして私たちの病院の同僚たち
Goodnight everybody
おやすみ皆さん
very happy today
今日はとても幸せです
we are also we have great honor
私たちもそうです、とても光栄です
Can invite us to Taiwan
私たちを台湾に招待してもらえますか
The Great Patriarch of the Healthcare Industry
ヘルスケア業界の偉大な家長
Director Qiu Wenda Qiu
監督 クイ・ウェンダ クイ
Come tell us about his 25 years
彼の25年間について話してください
research done on neurotrauma
神経外傷に関して行われた研究
Director Qiu Wenda in the United States
邱文達監督（アメリカ）
University of Pizza Earns Ph.D.
ピザ大学が博士号を取得
Also at Nihon University's School of Medicine
日本大学医学部にも
PhD in Neurology
神経学博士号
Then he was at Taipei Medical University
その後、彼は台北医科大学にいました
served many important
多くの重要な役割を果たした
Administrative portfolio includes Director of Neurosurgery
管理ポートフォリオには脳神経外科部長が含まれる
Head of Department of Public Health
公衆衛生局長
Director of the Injury Prevention Institute
傷害予防研究所所長
Taipei Medical University
台北医科大学
Vice President of Hospital
病院副院長
Then the vice-principal and the principal
それから教頭先生と校長先生
Director Qiu is also a professor of Doctoral Program in Neurological Disorders
邱所長は神経疾患博士課程の教授でもあります。
and the director of the Center of Excellence in Clinical Research
臨床研究センター・オブ・エクセレンスの所長
everybody knows
誰もが知っている
The Department of Health's job is not a good job to do
保健省の仕事は良い仕事ではない
But Director Qiu was recruited by the government in 2011
しかし、邱所長は2011年に政府に採用された。
As the Director of the Department of Health, it has been quite smooth so far
保健省の局長として、これまでのところ非常に順調です
Compared with the previous directors, they have done a good job
前の監督に比べたら、彼らは良い仕事をした
and we thank him
そして私たちは彼に感謝します
Our health depends on his protection
私たちの健康は彼の保護にかかっています
In addition to doing some academic administrative work, Director Qiu
邱所長は学術事務の仕事に加えて、
He is also in academic research
彼は学術研究にも携わっています
A well-known leading scholar in neurotrauma research at home and abroad
国内外で著名な神経外傷研究の第一人者
He once served as the chairman of four important medical associations in China
彼はかつて中国の 4 つの重要な医師協会の会長を務めていました。
Society of Surgeons and Neurosurgery
外科医および脳神経外科協会
Neurotrauma and Injury Prevention
神経外傷と傷害の予防
These are the presidents and directors of the largest medical associations in China.
彼らは中国最大の医師会の会長や理事たちだ。
that's not easy
それは簡単ではありません
He has also served as the president of three international associations
彼は 3 つの国際協会の会長も務めました。
and Secretary General of the Neurotrauma Committee of the World Association of Neurosurgery
および世界脳神経外科協会神経外傷委員会事務局長
And participated in the editing of five international journals
5つの国際雑誌の編集に参加
And he is also a new publisher of an international journal
そして彼は国際ジャーナルの新しい発行者でもあります
So everyone knows this one
だからこれはみんな知ってるよ
Qiu Shuchang is actually very careful in taking care of patients
Qiu Shuchang は実際に患者の世話をするのに非常に慎重です
Caring for patients and giving them a lot of love
患者さんを思いやり、たくさんの愛情を注ぐ
Also doing quite well in academic research
学術研究でもかなりの成績を収めている
And more outstanding in academic administration
そして学術行政においてさらに優れた
So we have a scholar like this
こんな学者がいるのですね
to serve as Director of the Department of Health
保健局長
It is the blessing of our people, really
それは本当に私たちの人々の祝福です
I have also known Qiu Shuchang for many years
私は邱淑昌を長年知っています
I also admire his academic achievements.
私は彼の学業成績も高く評価しています。
Qiu Shuchang made a great contribution to Taiwan
邱樹昌は台湾に多大な貢献をした
We say you only need to save one life
救える命は1つだけだと言います
you can go to heaven
あなたは天国に行くことができます
Qiu Shuchang not only saved one life
邱樹昌は一人の命を救っただけではない
He killed more than 3,000 people a year
彼は年間3000人以上を殺害した
so he's going to heaven now
だから彼は今天国に行くでしょう
This, Director Zhuo, has been independent all his life in the legislation that motor vehicles are grinders with helmets
周長官は、自動車はヘルメットをかぶった車両であるという法律に生涯を通じて独立してきました。
Everyone knows that accidents were the third leading cause of death in Taiwan
台湾における死亡原因の第 3 位が事故であることは誰もが知っています。
That's quite a lot of deaths
かなりの死者数ですね
Then every time we see a very young person
それからとても若い人を見るたびに
Sudden injury from a motor vehicle, then brain trauma and death
自動車による突然の怪我、その後脳外傷により死亡
The family is having a hard time and then his siblings are having a hard time
家族は大変な思いをしているが、彼の兄弟たちも大変な思いをしている
But the best way to prevent this is to wear this helmet
しかし、これを防ぐ最善の方法は、このヘルメットを着用することです
As for Director Zhuo, it is actually not easy to promote this activity.
朱所長にとって、この活動を推進するのは実は簡単ではありません。
Need to have good academic research results
優れた学術研究成果が必要
And you have to be very determined to join the so-called social movement
そしていわゆる社会運動に参加するには強い決意が必要です
Appeal to everyone in the so-called society to pay attention to
いわゆる社会のすべての人に注意を払うよう訴えます
Moreover, legislation is required to promote the promotion of this hard hat
さらに、このヘルメットの普及を促進するには法律が必要です
able to move smoothly
スムーズに移動できる
After Director Zhuo promoted the legislation of such hard hats?
卓長官がそのようなヘルメットの法制化を推進した後は？
In fact, the accident
実はその事故、
Injuries have dropped from the third to the sixth cause of death
怪我は死因の第3位から第6位に減少
3,000 fewer deaths per year
年間死亡者数が 3,000 人減少
This contributes greatly to the health of our people
これは人々の健康に大きく貢献します
that in the field of traumatic brain injury research
外傷性脳損傷研究の分野で
Our academic journal
私たちの学術雑誌
It also ranks third in the world
世界でも3位にランクされています
So it's quite an achievement
それはかなりの成果です
Of course you can imagine
もちろん想像できるでしょう
Director Qiu must have won many, many awards
邱監督はきっとたくさんの賞を受賞しているはずだ
It's very long if we practice it all
全部練習したらすごく長いよ
I only read a few
ほんの数冊しか読んでいない
Including the Individual Special Contribution Award of the 17th Medical Dedication Award
第17回医療献身賞個人特別貢献賞を含む
Hua Mingning's Medical Contribution Award
華明寧の医療貢献賞
There is also the Legacy of the University of Pittsburgh in the United States
アメリカのピッツバーグ大学の遺産もあります
Lolriot Winners
ロルリオットの勝者
and this Contribution Research Award from the Asia Pacific Alliance for Public Health
そしてアジア太平洋公衆衛生同盟からのこの貢献研究賞
more than ten awards
10以上の賞を受賞
So we can invite Director Qiu today
今日は邱所長をお招きします
come give us a speech
来て私たちにスピーチをしてください
It's an honor for all of us
私たち全員にとって光栄なことです
then we
それから私たち
welcome with warm applause
温かい拍手でお出迎え
Director Qiu came to give us a speech today
今日は邱所長が講演に来られました
Thanks
ありがとう
Thank you Vice President Chen
陳副社長に感謝します
introduce
導入
Then thank you for the opportunity to come here to share with you this time.
それでは、この度はここに来てお話しする機会をいただきましてありがとうございます。
So
それで
I think this 25 years in fact I
この25年は実際に私は
graduate
卒業
up to now
今まで
37, 38 years
37、38歳
So what have you been doing for the past ten years?
それで、あなたはこの10年間何をしていましたか？
I'll probably tell you
たぶん教えてあげるよ
Then the past ten years have been in
それから過去10年間は
Managing patients with traumatic brain injuries
外傷性脳損傷患者の管理
or a brain tumor or something these patients
あるいは脳腫瘍か何かの患者たち
Most of them are doing surgery. What?
彼らのほとんどは手術を受けています。
So
それで
I haven't
私はそうではありません
When I entered prevention, I mostly did clinical work.
予防に入ったときは主に臨床の仕事をしていました。
clinical work is like this
臨床の仕事はこんな感じです
then for example
それなら例えば
Let's talk about car accidents
交通事故について話しましょう
then in
それから
Usually we used to be very early
通常、私たちはとても早く来ていました
in the 1980s
1980年代に
The students were involved in car accidents at about five o'clock in the afternoon
学生たちは午後5時ごろに交通事故に遭った
Five point trauma or six point trauma
5 点トラウマまたは 6 点トラウマ
then sent to a small hospital
その後、小さな病院に送られました
Small hospital is sending
小さな病院が送っています
It's dangerous to see this
これを見ると危険です
send it to the big hospital
大きな病院に送ってください
The big hospital got there around seven or eight o'clock
大きな病院は7時か8時頃に到着しました
Then start the treatment or start the examination
その後、治療または検査を開始します
check check fiddle
チェックチェックフィドル
after finishing
終わった後
just start again
もう一度始めてください
Tell the patient again
もう一度患者さんに伝えます
to be operated on
手術を受ける
Then watch the patient operate
その後、患者の手術を観察します
Because many patients have no family members
家族がいない患者も多いため、
often without family
家族がいないことが多い
and very young
そしてとても若い
At that time, most of them were people in their twenties.
当時は20代の人が多かったです。
no family
家族がいない
Otherwise, when family members come
それ以外の場合は、家族が来たときに
almost eleven o'clock
ほぼ11時
so we start the operation
それで作戦を開始します
almost twelve o'clock
ほぼ12時
after eleven o'clock
11時以降
Every day is almost five days a week
毎日がほぼ週5日です
open till dawn
夜明けまで営業
often open till dawn
夜明けまで開いていることが多い
Then I often sleep in the car
それから車の中で寝ることが多いです
fall down
落ちる
Then go to the clinic again
それからまたクリニックへ行ってください
life like this
こんな人生
then
それから
I always think so
いつもそう思う
one day i sat there
ある日、私はそこに座っていました
when waking up in the car
車の中で目覚めたとき
Hey, this is too much
おい、これは多すぎる
too many accidents
事故が多すぎる
Do you want to find a way to go
進むべき道を見つけたいですか
Do you want to come
来たいですか
do something
何かをする
take precautions
予防策を取る
just thought of saying
今言おうと思った
Hey, very few people wear hard hats
ねえ、ヘルメットをかぶっている人はほとんどいません
At that time, less than 5% of people wore hard hats
当時、ヘルメットを着用している人は 5% 未満でした
I just want to say that I should make a hard hat.
ヘルメットを作るべきだと言いたいだけです。
So this is the previous story
それでは前回のお話です
It's all about cutting
すべてはカットすることです
that's there
それはそこにあります
before the lecture
講義の前に
I'll talk to you guys first because I'm watching today
今日見てるから先に話しておこう
I thought it was all like
全部そうだと思ってた
There are many scholars like Professor Chen
陳教授のような学者はたくさんいる
So I use English today
だから今日は英語を使います
present but
存在するが
There are a lot of pictures, it doesn't matter
写真はたくさんありますが、問題ありません
I speak Chinese
私は中国語を話します
then let me tell you first
それなら最初に言っておきます
what does a brain injury look like
脳損傷はどのようなものですか
why is it called tofu
なぜ豆腐と呼ばれるのか
Brain is almost the same as tofu
脳は豆腐とほぼ同じ
Its hardness is not much different
硬さはあまり変わらない
It's just that it has an extra layer of membrane package
膜パッケージの追加層があるだけです
arachnoid pack
クモ膜パック
So it's fixed form
なので定型です
And then it has a lot of blood vessels
そして血管がたくさんある
blood vessels many blood vessels
血管 たくさんの血管
probably so
おそらくそうだろう
Its hardness is about the same
硬さはほぼ同じです
It's similar to tofu, which is firmer tofu.
木綿豆腐のような感じです。
So this brain hit the ground
それでこの脳は地面にぶつかった
it's broken cracked
壊れてひび割れている
But I can't sew, I can't sew
でも私は縫えない、縫えない
So it's broken it's broken
だから壊れた、壊れた
it a lot of people after brain injury
脳損傷後に多くの人がそうなる
it got recovery just what
それは回復しました
Just a reward function
ただの報酬関数
Is to use other areas to reward
報酬を得るために他の領域を使用することです
So the brain is broken and never recovers.
つまり、脳は壊れてしまい、回復することはありません。
what about this brain
この脳はどうなっているのか
What happens when we get hurt
怪我をすると何が起こるのか
The first one will produce
最初のものは生成します
Our mildest is called a concussion
最も軽いものは脳震盪と呼ばれます
Everyone, maybe most people think that
皆さん、もしかしたらほとんどの人がそう思っているかもしれません
Wow, a serious concussion
うわー、重度の脳震盪だ
Concussion, actually concussion is
脳震盪、実際には脳震盪は
One day his bones are like this
ある日彼の骨はこうなった
But just faint
でもただ気絶するだけ
you don't hold up anymore
あなたはもう我慢しません
But the brain
しかし、脳は
No structural damage seen
構造的な損傷は見られません
Structural damage cannot be seen
構造的なダメージは見当たりません
This is called a concussion
これを脳震盪といいます
in our general
私たちの一般的には
He was unconscious for less than five minutes.
彼は5分も経たないうちに意識を失った。
very slight
非常にわずかな
Well, if you have a brain contusion, it's more serious.
まあ、脳挫傷の場合はさらに深刻です。
brain contusion is what can see
脳挫傷は目に見えるものです
I owe even
偶欠偶欠
bruising phenomenon
あざ現象
it's called a brain contusion
脳挫傷といいます
constitutional brain
体質的な脳
brain contusion
脳挫傷
The coma will last longer
昏睡状態が長引くだろう
That's an injury
それは怪我だよ
But the worst thing is
しかし、最も最悪なことは、
really bad brain trauma
本当にひどい脳外傷
episodic hemorrhage
突発性出血
This is all scary
これはすべて怖いです
What about after this episodic hemorrhage?
この突発的な出血の後はどうなるでしょうか？
often have this phenomenon
この現象がよくある
that is
あれは
Brain injury right after the car accident
交通事故直後の脳損傷
After a while
しばらくして
maybe a concussion
もしかしたら脳震盪かもしれない
But one of them
しかしそのうちの1人は
Broken blood vessel
壊れた血管
he bleeds slowly
彼はゆっくりと出血する
Patient, you see that kid was fine when he came home.
患者さん、あの子は家に帰ってきたときは元気でしたね。
when i got home i said
家に帰ったとき私は言いました
I had a fight with my classmates
クラスメイトと喧嘩した
Or create something for the car
または車用に何かを作成する
After returning home
帰宅後
He said he had a headache
彼は頭が痛いと言った
want to go to sleep
寝たいです
Well, mom, if you pay attention, it's fine.
まあ、お母さん、注意していれば大丈夫ですよ。
If you don't pay attention, you will see
注意しないと見えてしまいます
The child suddenly started humming loudly at night
その子供は夜に突然大声で鼻歌を歌い始めた
weird kids snoring
いびきをかいている奇妙な子供たち
because he can't breathe
彼は息ができないから
respiratory tract is not very good
気道の状態があまり良くない
just unconscious
ただ無意識に
Then there are children
それから子供たちもいる
Sent to the hospital for surgery to save him
彼を救うために手術のために病院に送られる
but
しかし
Many of them may not be saved
それらの多くは保存されない可能性があります
if you're not careful at night
夜は気をつけないと
so he often
だから彼はよく
Sometimes there will be a delay in happening
場合によっては遅延が発生する場合があります
He woke up with a concussion first
彼は最初に脳震盪で目が覚めた
But what about when we go back?
しかし、戻ったらどうなるでしょうか？
Bleeding again or getting bad again
また出血したり、また悪化したり
or how
あるいはどうやって
So this brain injury is complicated
したがって、この脳損傷は複雑です
then we almost
それから私たちはほとんど
I also hand it over to you today
今日もお渡しします
five tips
5つのヒント
Even a brain injury is important
脳損傷さえも重要です
Tips everyone should know
誰もが知っておくべきヒント
that is
あれは
what about the first one
最初のものはどうですか
Brain injury, you must pay attention to it
脳損傷、注意が必要です
do you have a headache
頭痛があるの
getting stronger
強くなる
or especially getting stronger
または特に強くなっている
The second one started vomiting
二人目は嘔吐し始めた
We usually have more than two
通常は2つ以上あります
Occasional vomiting is common in children
時折嘔吐することは子供によく見られます
But what if more and more
でも、もっともっと増えたらどうなるか
or more than twice
または2回以上
take it slow and be careful
ゆっくりと注意してください
what about the third one
3番目はどうですか
See if the consciousness has deteriorated
意識が低下していないか確認する
It's just that people don't know clearly
それは人々がはっきりと知らないだけです
so sometimes
だから時々
Wake him up often
彼を頻繁に起こしてください
So the fourth one is
それで4番目は
often have to wake him up
頻繁に彼を起こさなければならない
every first night
最初の夜ごとに
maybe every hour to wake him up
おそらく1時間ごとに彼を起こしてください
wake him up
彼を起こす
or the next day
または翌日
maybe gone
たぶんなくなった
It's gone, it's always like this
消えてしまった、いつもこうだ
What about the last one?
最後のものはどうですか？
if anything
何かあれば
what's changed in particular
特に何が変わったのか
Which aspect has changed?
どの側面が変わりましたか?
or how he will happen
あるいは彼がどうなるか
many complications
多くの合併症
then be careful
それなら気をつけて
It's better to go to the doctor quickly
早く医者に行ったほうがいいですよ
So generally speaking
一般的に言えば
he has a lot of symptoms
彼にはたくさんの症状がある
Wait a minute and I'll mention a lot of symptoms
ちょっと待ってください。たくさんの症状について説明します
But observation is the most important thing
でも一番大切なのは観察です
Especially the changes in his process
特に彼のプロセスの変化
So in a brain injured person
つまり、脳に損傷を負った人の場合
is very important
はとても重要です
So this brain injury is important
したがって、この脳損傷は重要です
intermediate prevention of these
これらの中間予防
Well, there's actually one more
いや、実はもう一つあるのですが、
More importantly, the sequelae
それよりも大事なのは後遺症
Except you have to save him in the acute stage
急性期で彼を救わなければならないことを除いて
What about the sequelae? It's terrible.
後遺症はどうなるのでしょうか? ひどいですね。
What about the aftermath?
余波はどうですか？
What if ordinary people
普通の人だったらどうするの
he produces a slight
彼はわずかな音を立てます
Severe trauma, he must have sequelae
重度のトラウマ、後遺症があるに違いない
his finger
彼の指
he must have sequelae
彼には後遺症があるに違いない
His hands and feet are bad
手も足も悪い
or generate
または生産する
Lungs or something
肺か何か
But what about a mild concussion?
しかし、軽い脳震盪の場合はどうでしょうか？
Recently, more and more sequelae have been found
最近は後遺症も増えている
then probably
それならおそらく
you pay attention
あなたは注意してください
If we roughly collected literature from all over the world
世界中の文献をざっくり集めてみたら
Probably at least 30 kinds
少なくとも30種類はあるだろう
30 kinds
30種類
Bad from long term memory
長期記憶のせいで悪い
headache dizziness various
頭痛 めまい いろいろ
probably collected
おそらく集められた
can't concentrate
集中できない
tinnitus insomnia blah blah blah
耳鳴り、不眠症、何とか何とか何とか
There are about 30 kinds in total
全部で30種類くらいあります
So what about the aftermath?
では、その後の影響はどうなるのでしょうか？
In fact, it has a lot to do with your rest the last two weeks.
実際、それは過去 2 週間の休息と大きく関係しています。
So generally we tell patients
したがって、一般的に私たちは患者さんにこう言います。
It's just about the first two weeks to rest.
休むのは最初の2週間くらいです。
Then this is a comparison
それでは比較です
At the same time, some others also found
同時に、他の人も見つけました
That is, even if the patient fully recovered
つまり、たとえ患者が完全に回復したとしても、
he can't see what the symptoms are like
彼には症状がどのようなものであるかがわかりません
but if you
しかし、もしあなたが
while giving him a test called neurobehavioral
彼に神経行動学的検査と呼ばれる検査をしたとき
Neurobehavioral tests are now more and more developed
神経行動検査は現在ますます開発されています
then you will find out
そうすれば分かるでしょう
What about him
彼についてはどうですか
This is about 30% of people
これは約30％の人に当てはまります
sometimes weird
時々奇妙です
What about this weird one?
この奇妙なものはどうですか？
Only his dearest mother
彼の最愛の母親だけが
or his wife
または彼の妻
or a spouse
または配偶者
or what
または何
he knows he's changing
彼は自分が変わっていることを知っている
so this
したがって、この
Brain injuries are really complicated
脳損傷は本当に複雑です
That's because he's like tofu
豆腐みたいだから
So there is no way to recover this tofu
したがって、この豆腐を回復する方法はありません
Therefore, it is still necessary to do the function of prevention
なので、まだ予防策です
Then I'll probably put this more basic try first
それから、おそらくこのより基本的な試みを最初に行うでしょう
let me tell you first
最初に言わせてください
And then we start looking at this
そして、これを見始めます
why do we do these things
なぜ私たちはこんなことをするのか
then see the next one
それから次を見てください
So maybe I'll introduce
なので紹介してみようかな
What is the significance of setting up this center over there?
あそこにこのセンターを設立する意義は何ですか？
Then we will tell you what is called transformation research.
次に、変革研究と呼ばれるものについて説明します。
Finally we look at our recent research
最後に最近の研究を見てみましょう
future direction
今後の方向性
I will talk about transformation research for about 25 minutes
変革研究について25分ほどお話します
I will talk about the current research below for about 30 minutes
以下、現在の研究について30分ほどお話します。
Then the previous research is life-saving for us.
その場合、以前の研究は私たちにとって命を救います。
Later, I found out that the sequelae caused by it were too many problems.
後から知ったのですが、それによる後遺症があまりにも問題でした。
So the latter is saving something
したがって、後者は何かを節約しています
functional improvements
機能改善
Just remembering this and see if it helps
これを思い出して、役立つかどうかを確認してください
how do i do this
どうすればいいですか
So probably my focus today is to mention the next one
おそらく今日の私の焦点は次のことについて言及することです
So why do this research
ではなぜこの研究をするのか
This has just been possible because it is very serious
非常に深刻な問題だからこそ、これが可能になったのです
because it is tofu
豆腐だから
tofu victim
豆腐被害者
After the injury, he has a very serious mortality rate
負傷後の死亡率は非常に高い
There are a lot of things like morbidity rate and comorbidities
罹患率や併存疾患などいろいろあります
So it has a very big impact on society and the economy
社会や経済に非常に大きな影響を与える
What about the whole world, what about a year
全世界はどうだろう、1年はどうだろう
Approximately 9 million people experience traumatic brain injury
約900万人が脳外傷に苦しんでいる
As for Taiwan, about 100,000 a year
台湾は年間約10万人
The 100,000 is just to go to the hospital to seek medical treatment
10万は病院に行って治療を受けるためのものです
There are only 100,000 people, and there are probably even more people who did not go to the hospital
人口は10万人しかいないし、病院に行かなかった人はもっといるだろう
Then this may be more than three times
そうすると3倍以上になるかも知れません
So why in America recently
ではなぜ最近アメリカで
attach great importance to this thing
このことを非常に重視する
Because of the wars in Iraq and Afghanistan
イラクとアフガニスタンでの戦争のせいで
What about many American soldiers?
多くのアメリカ兵はどうですか？
did not die on the battlefield
戦場では死ななかった
But after he returned to his hometown, he began to have a lot of sequelae
しかし、故郷に戻った後、彼は重い後遺症を抱え始めました。
memory starts to decline
記憶力が低下し始める
then start to have a headache
それから頭痛がし始める
dizziness poor balance
めまい、平衡感覚の低下
Insomnia occurs many times
不眠症が何度も起こる
In fact, some people don't feel that there is any serious injury at all.
実際、大きな怪我をしていると全く感じない人もいます。
But it's the same when he comes back
でも彼が戻ってきたら同じだ
So these problems have caused the whole world to study this so-called
これらの問題により、全世界がいわゆるこの問題を研究することになりました。
Brain Trauma Research
脳外傷研究
In particular, the WHO also has more and more disasters
特にWHOも災害が増えています。
Therefore, special emphasis is placed on the importance of brain trauma.
したがって、脳外傷の重要性が特に強調されます。
next
次
this is 1987
これは1987年です
then we will
それなら私たちはそうします
Did a simple research and found out that
簡単な調査を行ったところ、次のことが分かりました
Taiwan is probably
台湾はおそらく
It's probably the area with the worst traumatic brain injury.
おそらく、外傷性脳損傷が最も深刻な領域です。
we found this
私たちはこれを見つけました
The most serious patient he than
彼よりも最も深刻な患者
about twice as much outside
外では2倍くらい
so moderate
とても適度な
Of course we use
もちろん私たちが使っているのは
Grasco Comasca
グラスコ コマスカ
This is a two table to measure
これは測定する 2 つのテーブルです
3 to 8 points are called severe
3～8点を重症といいます。
9 to 12 points are called
9〜12ポイントがコールされます
Moderate
中等度
12 to 15 points are called mild
12～15点を軽度と言います。
We found that mild
私たちはそれが穏やかであることを発見しました
rarely less
めったに少ない
The whole is more serious
全体はもっと深刻です
next
次
so
それで
It was the locomotive at that time
当時の機関車です
In 1987, there were only 7 million locomotives
1987 年には機関車はわずか 700 万両しかありませんでした
Now it has reached 14 million
今では1400万に達しました
So
それで
All the vehicles inside this one
この中にあるすべての車両
all vehicles approximately
ほぼすべての車両
If there were about 10 million vehicles at that time
当時、自動車が1000万台くらいあったとしたら
Of the 10 million vehicles, 7 million are locomotives
1,000万台の車両のうち、700万台が機関車です
so serious
真剣
And what?
そして何？
Few people wear hard hats
ヘルメットをかぶっている人はほとんどいません
so so
まあまあ
Top 10 causes of death at the time
当時の死因トップ10
are hurt
みんな傷ついています
accident injury
事故による怪我
So this is very serious in Taiwan
台湾ではこれは非常に深刻です
But at that time everyone was used to it
でもその頃はみんな慣れてた
public security
公安
A lot of people are like, if we talk about prevention or something
予防などについて話すと、多くの人はこうなります。
They'll all tell you, ah, there's no way this accident could have been prevented.
彼らは皆、ああ、この事故を防ぐことはできなかった、と言うでしょう。
But in fact, prevention is the most effective
でも実は予防が一番効果があるのです
So at that time, I couldn't find any information.
ですので、当時は情報が見つかりませんでした。
Because health insurance hasn't started yet, health insurance has just started
健康保険はまだ始まっていないので、健康保険は始まったばかりです
Well, so, there were very few preventive strategies at the time.
そのため、当時は予防策がほとんどありませんでした。
So this is Taiwan, why was it serious at that time?
ここは台湾ですが、なぜ当時は深刻だったのでしょうか？
Next I think this is the center of our establishment
次に、ここが私たちの施設の中心だと思います
Divided into four groups, I won’t talk about this one. The next one
4つのグループに分かれているので、今回は割愛します。
What about so-called translational studies?
いわゆるトランスレーショナルスタディーズについてはどうでしょうか？
Just want scientists, doctors
科学者や医師が欲しいだけ
and many of our research institutes
そして私たちの研究機関の多くは
Like the National Institutes of Health and cooperation with NIDA in the United States
米国の国立衛生研究所やNIDAとの協力のように
INIH in the United States is the cooperation of the National Institutes of Health
米国のINIHは国立衛生研究所の協力によるものです。
Then our whole study
それから私たちの研究全体が
Much of this process is carried out together with these institutions.
このプロセスの多くは、これらの機関と協力して実行されます。
next
次
Then of course you need a lot of equipment
そうなると当然色々な機材が必要になります
including genes
遺伝子も含めて
include this
これを含めて
spectrometer these
分光計これら
tissue bank
組織庫
What's more special is the functional MRI
さらに特別なのは機能的MRIです
Then we just bought one too
それから私たちも1つ購入しました
the best
最高の
the latest in the world
世界上現在最新的
So our function for this memory
したがって、このメモリに対する関数は
also did a lot
もたくさんやった
Then again it is very important for this
もう一度言いますが、これは非常に重要です
IRB
治験審査委員会
that is
あれは
research ethics
研究倫理
This and this clinical trial center
この治験センターとこの治験センター
this is very important
これはとても重要です
one
一個
Core Facility is our main research
コア施設は私たちの主な研究です
center
中心
next
次
Then we are at Taipei Medical University
さて、台北医科大学です
in fact
実際には
At that time, many of the schools were doing clinical trials.
当時、多くの学校が臨床試験を行っていました。
especially in nerve
特に神経において
Medicine, then we have three hospitals running at the same time
医療では、3 つの病院が同時に運営されています
of course for this
もちろんこれのために
Ethical review is very strict
倫理審査は非常に厳しい
Then also through WHO's FIRCAP
その後、WHOのFIRCAPを通じて
These next ones, in fact, we
これらの次のものは、実際には、私たち
The other six hospitals in the province have a total of more than 8,700 beds
州内の他の 6 つの病院には合計 8,700 床以上のベッドがあります。
have a common doing this
これをするのが一般的です
Collaborative Research Understanding
共同研究の理解
next
次
then this is where we are
それならここが私たちのいる場所です
This is a famous Elsep
有名なエルセップです
them
彼ら
Made one called Cyber ​​Sport
サイバースポーツというものを作りました
Cyber Sport Light
サイバースポーツライト
That said, the world's research on traumatic brain injury
そうは言っても、外傷性脳損傷に関する世界の研究は
it ranks in the end
それは最終的にランク付けされます
its publication and its influence
その出版とその影響
What about our first time in 2007?
2007 年に初めて行ったときはどうでしょうか?
enter the seventh place
7位に入る
That person's research is into the fourth place next
あの人の研究は次の4位に入っています
By 2009, we had entered the third place
2009 年までに、当社は 3 位に入りました。
Personally still in third place
個人的にはまだ3位
next
次
So what about 2011?
では、2011 年はどうでしょうか?
What about the word brain trauma?
脳外傷という言葉はどうでしょうか？
we've already run to the first place
私たちはすでに最初の場所まで走っています
then in this
それからこの中で
Personally still third
個人的にはまだ3位
So the whole research aspect
研究面全体としては
Our range is pretty wide
私たちの範囲はかなり広いです
wait a minute everyone can see
ちょっと待ってください、誰でも見ることができます
We are working on the four levels of depression
私たちはうつ病の 4 つのレベルに取り組んでいます
next
次
sorry
ごめん
this
これ
The voice is hoarse
声がかすれている
wait a minute i tell you why
ちょっと待ってください、理由をお話します
So what is repression medicine?
抑制医学とは何ですか?
Depression medicine was first proposed
うつ病の治療法が最初に提案された
This is all copied from the US National Institutes of Health
これはすべて国立衛生研究所からコピーしたものです
Depression medicine is of course from
うつ病の薬はもちろん
Enter this from Basic Medicine
基礎医学からこれを入力してください
Use basic medicine to the last
基礎医学のものを最後まで使い切る
Applying it to humans is depression-reversal medicine
これを人間に応用すればうつ病を回復する薬となる
next
次
Then repression research is repression
ならば抑圧研究は抑圧だ
Use this underline basis for translational medicine
翻訳医療にはこの下線の基礎を使用してください
it's mostly transfer research
主に転移研究です
That is to say, from a team of scientists
つまり、科学者チームから
scientist link到 basic science
科学者と基礎科学のつながり
clinical research
臨床研究
Then take the result of this base
次に、このベースの結果を取得します
clinical career
臨床経歴
It is used in clinical daily treatment
日常の臨床治療に使用されています
This is called transferring some
これを一部転送といいます
that is
あれは
For example, experts from animal
たとえば、動物の専門家
Slowly research out a lot of things
ゆっくり色々調べてください
reapply this thing to people
これを人々に再び適用する
This is called transfer
これを転送といいます
next
次
So a story in the US Capitol
米国議会議事堂での話
I also tell you
私もあなたに言います
It's America's national restroom.
アメリカの国営トイレです。
Do a lot of basic research
基礎研究をたくさんする
That basic research has been increasing
基礎研究が増えている
Then Congress couldn't take it anymore
そうなると議会はもう我慢できなくなった
that is
あれは
We don't want to know why
理由は知りたくない
because why has done too much
なぜやりすぎたのか
but they need to know
しかし彼らは知る必要がある
When can be applied to people
人に適用できる場合
That is to say, you do so much
つまり、それだけのことをするのです
dogs, cats, what
犬、猫、何
Then we don't think it's important
それなら私たちはそれが重要だとは思わない
When can these successful treatments
これらの治療が成功するのはいつになるのか
use it on people
人に対してそれを使う
So at that time
だからその時は
Head of NIH
NIH所長
It's called Alius Gehoni
アリウス・ゲホーニといいます
He invented a tool called Translational
彼はトランスレーショナルと呼ばれるツールを発明しました
Clinical Science comes out in New England Magazine
ニューイングランド・マガジンに臨床科学が掲載される
He used from Bench to Best Sight
彼はベンチからベストサイトまで使用しました
Bench is basic research to Best Sight to Practice
ベンチは基礎研究から実践までのベストサイトです
What about this idea?
このアイデアはどうでしょうか？
has been accepted by people all over the world
世界中の人々に受け入れられてきました
so
それで
It will gradually develop into the stage of T1 and T2
徐々にT1、T2の段階に発展していきます
Then in 2010 the next one
そして次は2010年
And developed into T1 to T4
T1～T4に発展
Then this has a greater impact on human beings
そうなると、人類に与える影響はさらに大きくなります
Not necessarily from cats and dogs
必ずしも猫や犬からではありません
Even from clinical research
臨床研究からも
be able to run to the benefit of all mankind
全人類の利益のために走ることができる
impact in the population
人口への影響
It's the whole population that helps
助けてくれるのは全国民です
This is a transfer
これは転送です
So the first transfer stage
最初の転送ステージでは
From basic to clinical application
基礎から臨床応用まで
What about the second clinic?
2番目のクリニックはどうですか？
turn it into something
それを何かに変える
called guidance
指導と呼ばれる
It is because of a lot of accumulated clinical experience
豊富な臨床経験の蓄積があるからです
turn it into a guide
それをガイドに変える
guideline means
ガイドラインの意味
Everyone can follow this line
誰もがこのラインに従うことができます
do something
何かをする
For example, the treatment of the external cavity of the head
たとえば、頭の外腔の治療
We accumulate from experience
経験から積み上げていく
From all aspects of research
研究のあらゆる側面から
make it a line
それを線にする
The line is then used on people
線は人々に適用されます
Apply it to all patients like this, everyone’s treatment methods will be compared
このように全ての患者さんに適用すると、全員の治療法が比較されます
The quality is relatively high and the standard is relatively high
品質は比較的高く、標準も比較的高い
Then you can use Gynein and Health Practice
その後、Gynein と Health Practice を使用できます。
Go to this and then apply to other, even another country or something
ここにアクセスして、他の国や何かに申請してください
This is Health Practice is Gynein
これが健康法です
So he divides this into T1 T2 T3
そこで彼はこれを T1 T2 T3 に分割します
Then Health Practice is based on these applications, and finally it is used on the population
次に、これらのアプリケーションに基づいて医療実践が行われ、最終的には国民に対して使用されます。
So today I will talk to you from these four directions.
そこで今日はこの4つの方向からお話をさせていただきます。
then the next one
それから次
What about the first one? Let me give you an example from basic medicine to clinical application.
1 つ目はどうでしょうか? 基礎医学から臨床応用までを例に挙げてみましょう。
Well, everyone knows that there is a drug called Propofol
さて、プロポフォールという薬があることは誰もが知っています
it will it is an antioxidant Antioxidant
それは抗酸化物質です
then it can also
それならそれもできます
have this neuroprotective function
この神経保護機能を持っています
This is already proof on the basis
これはすでに根拠に基づいて証明されています
So what if we apply it to people?
では、それを人に当てはめるとどうなるでしょうか？
In fact, this anesthesiology department has always been useful.
実際、この麻酔科はいつもお世話になっています。
So some patients work and some patients don't
つまり、働ける患者もいるし、働けない患者もいる
next
次
Then find out that this is useful
それから、これが便利であることがわかります
There is osracial of 2.8
オスラシアルは2.8あります
It's what helped this result
それがこの結果に貢献した
probably so
おそらくそうだろう
We have also published this in the literature
文献にも掲載させていただきました
next
次
Then in this process
それからこの過程で
We did about 7
7つくらいやったよ
4 of them compare with results
そのうちの 4 つは結果と比較します
Then I'll be Gynein soon
じゃあ、もうすぐギナインになるよ
Of course you don't need to talk
もちろん話す必要はありません
More fruitful is to say
もっと実りあるのは、
we find on animals
私たちは動物で見つけます
If you treat a patient with a brain sore
脳痛の患者を治療する場合
If you use a monitor
モニターを使用する場合
A catheter can measure the pressure in his brain
カテーテルで脳圧を測定できる
Constantly measure brain pressure
脳圧を常に測定
That is, the result of treatment will be much better
つまり、治療の結果がはるかに良くなります
If the pressure is high we put some water out
圧力が高い場合は水を出します
if or with some medicine
何らかの薬がある場合、または薬を使用している場合
This is better for patient outcomes
これは患者の転帰にとってより良いことです
Then this proves that he has 4.3 times the effect
すると、4.3倍の効果があることがわかります。
Is hyperbaric oxygen effective?
では、高圧酸素は効果があるのでしょうか？
high pressure
高圧
Hyperbaric Oxygen Chambers
高圧酸素室
So this proves that he works for subpolar patients
つまり、これは彼が亜寒帯患者のために働いていることを証明しています
But it doesn't help a lot with polarity
しかし、極性に関してはあまり役に立ちません
Then from this
それではこれから
Another special
もう一つのスペシャル
In treatment we use a
治療では私たちが使用するのは、
partial pressure, oxygen partial pressure directly into the brain
分圧、酸素分圧を脳に直接入力
Well, recently the whole world has also begun to be popular
さて、最近世の中も流行り始めてきましたね
What did it turn out to be?
結局のところどうなったのでしょうか？
What if you measure the partial pressure directly?
分圧を直接測定したらどうなるでしょうか?
he will turn out well
彼はうまくいくだろう
Then I think these details I will no longer
そうしたら、これらの詳細はもうやめると思います
What about this one, especially for people with lung problems?
これは、特に肺に問題のある人にとってはどうでしょうか?
If you have lung problems
肺に問題がある場合
you want to put it
それを置きたいですか
Oxygen pressure and oxygen height are more difficult
氧壓、氧身高比較困難
So however you can get from the machine
ただし、マシンから取得できます
Turn it up with a FIO2
FIO2 でレベルを上げる
This is especially useful for patients, and it is very helpful for patients with trauma
これは患者にとって特に有用であり、外傷を負った患者にとっても非常に役立ちます
So these are all evidence of T1, which means we have done
つまり、これらはすべて T1 の証拠です。つまり、私たちが行ったということです。
Then if T2 is based on clinical experience, make it Gaili guidelines
次に、T2 が臨床経験に基づいている場合は、Gaili ガイドラインにします
Then we made a Taiwan Gaili around 2007
その後、2007年頃に台湾ガイリを作りました。
This is all published in the literature
これはすべて文献に掲載されています
Then we will establish an Asian Gaili with Japan, South Korea, and China
そして、日本、韓国、中国とアジアガイリを設立します。
This is also in Gaili Nero, which is the magazine with the highest score in our neurotrauma
これは、私たちの神経外傷に関して最も高いスコアを獲得した雑誌である Gaili Nero にも掲載されています。
Then this, the next one I'll see...
じゃあこれ、次に見るのは…
Then this has been published in this, published in bilingual
それから、これはこれで出版され、バイリンガルで出版されました
Then whatever the book is published
そうすると、どんな本が出版されても、
And besides, he's also...
まあ、それに加えて、彼はまた...
Published in international literature
国際文献に掲載される
what about this one i wait
これはどうですか、待ってます
Now all our neurosurgeries use this
現在、すべての脳神経外科でこれが使用されています
doing treatment
治療を行っています
everyone has one
誰もが1つ持っています
something like a biboy
ビーボーイっぽいもの
Of course it's still being updated
もちろん今も更新中です
maybe wait a minute i brought the basics
ちょっと待ってください、基本的なものを持ってきました
then the first few
それから最初の数個
I can send you any questions
質問があればお送りします
next
次
Then we use the British Sign Level of Evidence
次に、英国のサインレベルの証拠を使用します。
to define him
彼を定義するために
evidence
証拠
next
次
Then
それから
Our recommendation also uses Sign Grade
私たちの推奨ではサイングレードも使用します
next
次
Then it includes these eight items
次に、これらの 8 つの項目が含まれます
emergency room treatment
救急室での治療
Determination of brain pressure
腦壓的測定
how to do it
どうやってするの
cerebral perfusion pressure
脳灌流圧
With this Fruits Therapy
このフルーツセラピーで
Then Sedative Nutrition these
次に、鎮静栄養これら
i will watch your brain
私はあなたの脳を観察します
I can
できます
the second one
2番目のもの
People's treatment of these next
次にこれらを個別に処理します
Then this is one of the consensus in Asia
これがアジアの共通認識の一つです
meeting next
次の会議
then we are probably here
それなら私たちはおそらくここにいるでしょう
this meeting this is not a
この会議はそうではありません
evidence base it is a consensus
証拠に基づいてそれはコンセンサスです
Then we have some consensus on these four themes
これら 4 つのテーマについてはある程度の合意が得られました
next
次
So, for example, what do you think, this brain pressure
それで、例えばどう思いますか、この脳圧
is a therapeutic concept, not just a tool
単なるツールではなく、治療上の概念です
Of course this has
もちろんこれには
My ventricle from the foreign ventricle is the most effective treatment
外国心室からの私の心室が最も効果的な治療法です
What about brain infusion pressure?
脳注入圧はどうでしょうか？
He thinks no less than 60
彼は60以上だと思っている
At the same time, this should not exceed 70
同時に、これは 70 を超えてはなりません
This is an important concept
これは重要な概念です
next
次
What about the other one? I think it is
もう 1 つはどうですか? そうだと思います
This is called decompression
これを減圧といいます
Open up the bones of the brain
脳の骨を開く
When the brain is swollen, the pressure can be squeezed out
脳が腫れると圧力が絞り出されることがある
We think this is also good
これも良いと思います
especially in very malignant brain tumors
特に非常に悪性の脳腫瘍の場合
Here I'm going to talk about a brain
ここで脳について話します
there are a lot of different
たくさんの異なるものがあります
This tofu nao is different from tofu
この豆腐なおは豆腐とは違います
The tofu shattered on the ground
豆腐は地面に砕け散った
But the brain has many blood vessels
しかし、脳には血管がたくさんあります
It has an omentum wrapped
大網が巻かれている
After being injured, it will take a while
怪我してからは時間がかかる
horribly swollen
ひどく腫れた
sometimes when you cut
時々カットするときに
when you turn it on
電源を入れると
That brain looks like this, what does it look like?
その脳はこんな感じですが、どんな感じですか？
We're called Dry Bread
私たちはドライブレッドと呼ばれています
It's like dry bread suddenly absorbs water
乾いたパンが突然水を吸収するようなものです
swell up so fast swell up very fast
とても早く膨らむ とても早く膨らむ
This is the same place in the brain
これは脳内の同じ場所です
because its blood flow is affected
血流に影響が出るので
Its venous return is not working
静脈還流が機能していない
swell so fast
とても早く膨らみます
So this sometimes this has to do a decompression
したがって、これは時々解凍を行う必要があります
Then the other sedatives are also considered to be
その場合、他の鎮静剤も同様であると考えられます。
Anti-oxidation is helpful for this generation defect rate
酸化防止はこの世代の不良率に役立ちます
next
次
then in the United States
それからアメリカで
In 200 years, the United States made a survey
200年後にアメリカは調査を行った
When entering Taiwan
台湾に入国するとき
We put America's one guide to the next
私たちはアメリカの 1 つのガイドを次のガイドに置きます
just take it
ただ受け取ってください
They believe that hyperventilation, political and economic agents
彼らは、過呼吸、政治的、経済的要因が原因であると信じています。
These political and economic agents are still useful
これらの政治的および経済的主体は依然として有用です
None of these hyperventilations help
これらの過呼吸はどれも機能しません
next
次
Let's see if it works locally
ローカルで動作するかどうか見てみましょう
We have treated more than 580 patients in Taiwan
私たちは台湾で580人以上の患者を治療してきました。
Proven brain pressure measurement on the first day
初日から実証済みの脳圧測定
with an average of one to three days
平均して 1 ～ 3 日
all meaningful
すべて意味のある
next
次
At the same time, it is meaningless for perfusion pressure
同時に、灌流圧は意味がありません。
Measuring means nothing
測定しても何の意味もない
It is also meaningless for breathing hyperventilation
過呼吸の場合も意味がありません
next
次
So the whole T3
つまり、T3全体
From empirical evidence to Health practice
経験的証拠から医療実践まで
We have about three larger ones
大きいのが3つほどあります
The first is that we put the American
1 つ目は、アメリカ人を配置することです。
It should be used in Taiwan
台湾でも使えばいいのに
think there is
あると思う
Then we did the case ourselves
それから私たちは自分たちで訴訟を起こしました
After you did the case yourself?
自分で訴訟を起こした後はどうですか？
now at present
今現在
Promoted by Taiwan Society of Neurosurgery
台湾脳神経外科学会が推進
then in addition
それからさらに
Our case in Asia
アジアにおける当社の事例
also did part
パートもした
Then this year will continue
それでは今年も続きます
Then come out one by one
じゃあ一人ずつ出てきて
then we'll use it to
それからそれを使ってみましょう
Asia
アジア
We have the same treatment model
私たちは同じ治療モデルを持っています
especially for asians
特にアジア人にとっては
everyone has
誰もが持っています
international consensus
国際的な合意
Then the treatment of patients will be better
そうすれば患者の治療も良くなる
This is what Action should come
これがアクションが来るべきものです
next
次
then there are many more
それならもっとたくさんあるよ
for example
例えば
we still have to do
私たちはまだやらなければなりません
this
これ
parenteral nutrition
非経口栄養
in 48 hours
48時間以内に
What about this patient?
この患者さんはどうでしょうか？
very helpful
非常に役立ちます
next
次
then in addition
それからさらに
WHO has a table on quality of life
WHOには生活の質に関する表があります
yes to this
はい、これに
quality of life
生活の質
Measurements are helpful
測定は役に立ちます
next
次
Um
えーっと
then compare
それから比較してください
interesting
面白い
Of course, this is a health insurance treatment file
もちろん健康保険診療ファイルです
We also found in the health insurance treatment files that
健康保険診療ファイルにも以下のことが分かりました。
The treatment file of this health insurance
この健康保険の治療ファイル
We found patients with brain injuries
脳損傷を負った患者を発見した
suddenly this
突然これ
skezophrenia is higher
skezophrenia比較高
this may have some
これにはいくつかあるかもしれません
citation problems
引用の問題
or the coding on the login
またはログイン時のコーディング
It was the problem of coding at that time
当時はコーディングの問題でした
But this is just a reference
でもこれは参考までに
The next one is the health insurance treatment file
次は健康保険診療ファイルです
This is also in our database
これは私たちのデータベースにもあります
The health insurance treatment file also found that
健康保険診療ファイルでも次のことが分かりました。
after brain injury
脳損傷後
its this
それはこれです
generate this
これを生成する
3 times higher rate of zeitgeist syndrome
時代精神症候群の発生率が 3 倍高い
will generate this in the future
将来これを生成します
This has been confirmed in many studies
これは多くの研究で確認されています
Especially the full phone
特にフルフォン
Nearly 60 to 70% of the majority have developed geriatric syndrome
大多数のほぼ60～70％が老人症候群を発症している
It doesn't have to be old age, it's arctimer, Alzheimer's disease
それは老衰である必要はありません、それはアークタイマー、アルツハイマー病です
So all over the world, there is a correlation between traumatic brain injury and the age and Alzheimer's
つまり、世界中で、外傷性脳損傷と年齢およびアルツハイマー病との間に相関関係があるということです。
Successive reports have been brought out
続々と報告が出てきました
The next one, more importantly, this is two studies
次の研究、さらに重要なのは、これは 2 つの研究です
For our future T3 to T4, one is the research of Professor Wang Longde
私たちの将来のT3からT4に向けて、1つは王隆徳教授の研究です。
He proves that wearing a helmet is better than not wearing a helmet
彼はヘルメットをかぶらないよりもヘルメットをかぶったほうが良いことを証明しました
The result is 2.6 times better than what we did ourselves 2.1 times better
結果は、自分たちで行った結果の 2.1 倍よりも 2.6 倍優れています
It is similar to international research, the next one
国際研究と似ていますが、次は
So let's talk about this fourth one, we call it T4
それでは、この 4 つ目のものについて話しましょう。T4 と呼びます。
From this Health practice to Health in
この健康実践から健康へ
impact in population
人口への影響
Here we are from 25 years
ここからは25年です
have been building a lot of databases
たくさんのデータベースを構築してきました
These four databases are relatively large
これら 4 つのデータベースは比較的大規模です
just have this
これだけ持ってて
There are more than 180,000 cases used in epidemiology
疫学では18万件以上の症例が使用されている
The clinical database has more than 2000 cases
臨床データベースには 2000 件を超える症例が含まれています
There are more than 1,400 cases of data registration of clinical water collection and provincial merchants
臨床用水の採取と地方の商店のデータ登録件数は1,400件以上
And here is the org library
そしてここが組織ライブラリです
About nearly 20,000 Samples
約20,000サンプル
This is Huadong's situation
これが華東の状況です
next
次
I don't need to talk about this
これについて話す必要はない
This is the org library
これは組織ライブラリです
This is what we discovered at the time
その時に発見したのがこれです
There are differences between Taipei and Hualien
台北と花蓮では違いがあります
The incidence rate in Hualien is about
花蓮の発生率は約
388 is twice that of Taipei
388は台北の2倍
The death rate in Hualien is four times that of Taipei.
花蓮の死亡率は台北の４倍だ。
And he has a higher ratio of truck to cargo
そして彼はトラックと貨物の比率が高い
next
次
We also found that the counties and cities in the east and outlying islands
また、東部および離島の郡および市でも、
Where the ratio of their locomotives is relatively high
機関車の比率が比較的高いところ
Their mortality rate and incidence rate are high
死亡率も発症率も高い
next
次
Then we were also in 1993 and 1997
それから1993年と1997年にも
Almost all the hospitals in the country have done
国内のほぼすべての病院が実施している
Then it can be concluded that this is dead 230
そうすれば、これは死んでいると結論付けることができます 230
About 230 people per 100,000 people
人口10万人あたり約230人
About 70% are caused by vehicles
約70％は車両が原因
That's a very high proportion in the world
世界的に見てもその割合は非常に高い
Then this was also published in the American Journal of Public Health
その後、これはAmerican Journal of Public Healthにも掲載されました
next
次
so the whole process
それでプロセス全体が
The most important thing for us is to promote the protection process
私たちにとって最も重要なことは、保護プロセスを促進することです
So I did a lot of research
それで私はたくさんの研究をしました
There is a way to push this
これを押す方法があります
this
これ
Hard hat legislation
ヘルメットに関する法律
then the next one
それから次
Of course, a lot of international comparisons have also been made.
もちろん、国際比較も数多く行われています。
use it to cite the next
次に引用するために使用します
Then this is the picture we often use
それから、これは私たちがよく使う写真です
Tell me all, let's see if you smile when you wear the hard hat this time
全部教えて、今度はヘルメットをかぶったときにあなたが笑うかどうか見てみましょう
This time it's in Portuguese, and I don't understand it either.
今回はポルトガル語なので私にもわかりません
it's a case a case
それはケース・ケースです
This is so funny I don't even have to talk
面白すぎて話す必要すらない
Everyone knows that the helmet is very funny
ヘルメットがとても面白いことは誰もが知っています
so we are in taipei
それで私たちは台北にいます
At that time in Taipei, in Taipei in 1984
1984年の台北、あの頃。
Just push hard hats, not without legislation
法律なしではなく、ヘルメットを押すだけです
At that time it was to fetch land
当時は土地を取得するためだった
Later, I found out that during these four months
後に判明したのですが、その4ヶ月以内に
in four months
4か月以内に
More than 500 people were mobilized by Taipei City Traffic Continental
台北市交通コンチネンタルにより500人以上が動員された
Crack down everywhere without wearing a hard hat
ヘルメットをかぶらずにどこでも取り締まろう
But soon you find out that
しかし、すぐにそれが分かります
The number of hospitalized patients has decreased by 30%
入院患者数は30％減少
Death rate reduced by 56%
死亡率が56%減少
was very surprised
とても驚きました
suddenly so much less
突然あまりにも少なくなった
At the time, people thought it couldn't be prevented.
当時、人々はそれを防ぐことはできないと考えていました。
It turned out that the wards were all empty.
病棟はすべて空室であることが判明した。
A third of the wards are empty
病棟の3分の1が空き部屋
So of course I was scolded by the MP
当然国会議員に叱られました
There is no legal basis for saying this, just ban it casually
これを言うのに法的根拠はなく、ただ単に禁止するだけです
They don't dare to catch it anymore
彼らはもうそれを捕まえようとはしない
then later
じゃあ後で
next
次
so in
それで
Through the middle process I would have had many times
途中の過程で何度もあっただろう
I took it all off
全部脱いでしまった
this is a lot of process
これは多くのプロセスです
Sometimes there's a parade, there's a Campan
時にはパレードもあるし、カンパンもある
do everything
すべてをする
even at public hearings
公聴会でも
in the legislature
立法府で
Very hard
とても厳しい
after more than three years
3年以上経ってから
Finally in 1997
ついに1997年に
Passed on June 1, 1986
1986 年 6 月 1 日に可決
next
次
This is before the legislation
これは法規制以前の話です
You see this man is very smart
この人はとても賢いのがわかりますね
full of wisdom
知恵に満ちた
next
次
This person is also good
この人もいいですね
He's the only one here
ここにいるのは彼だけだ
next
次
At that time began to ban
当時は禁止され始めた
one day
1日で出る
More than 10,000 slippery eggs
10,000個以上のぬるぬる卵
the whole country
全国
next
次
you see it's been a few days
数日が経ったのがわかりますか
become like this
こうなる
next
次
This can still be legal
これはまだ合法である可能性があります
when i speak abroad
海外で話すとき
I talked about this
このことについて話しました
i thought it was a joke
冗談だと思った
Then someone really got up and asked me
すると誰かが本当に起き上がって私に尋ねました
how do you promote
どのように宣伝しますか
animal hard hat
動物のヘルメット
i can't tell
言えません
next
次
this is in Taichung
ここは台中にあります
look at this
これを見てください
it's over 100%
それは100％を超えています
Then you see so much of this one
そうすると、これをたくさん見ることができます
I only see a hard hat that looks like a fake
偽物っぽいヘルメットしか見えない
So this effect is pretty good
なのでこの効果はかなり良いです
then let's see how it turns out
それではどうなるか見てみましょう
next
次
you see usually start here
通常はここから始まることがわかります
this is taipei
ここは台北です
It turned out to be at 7300
7300になった
around 7400
7400左右
Then the motor vehicle accident injury
それから、交通事故による怪我
just keep falling
ただ落ち続けるだけ
Fall here and leave around 4300
ここで落ちて4300頃出発
Recently dropped to around 3600
最近は3600くらいまで下がった
More recent what CBL
最近のCBLって何？
everything is coming
すべてがやってくる
so
それで
The final proof is
最終的な証拠は、
it helps
助けになる
some people asked me
何人かの人が私に尋ねました
Is that because the number of cars is decreasing?
車の数が減ったからでしょうか？
my next one
私の次のもの
No car has been increasing
車が全然増えてない
Now it has reached 14 million
今では1400万に達しました
Increased by 82% over the past 10 years
過去 10 年間で 82% 増加
Then the population also increases
そうすれば人口も増える
11% increase
11%増加
Admission increased by 10.5%
入場料は10.5%増加
But the death rate dropped by 51%
しかし死亡率は51%減少した
next
次
This is very important to our public health
これは公衆衛生にとって非常に重要です
potential loss of life
人命損失の可能性
Very helpful especially for this young person
特にこの若い人にとっては非常に役立ちます
so i believe
だから私は信じます
not only saved a lot of people
多くの人を救っただけでなく
but saved the young man
しかし若者を救った
this is more important
これはもっと重要です
next
次
You can see that we have been
私たちが行ってきたことがわかります
This is nearly 30 years
これはもう30年近くになる
Both are the third of the top ten babies
どちらもトップ10の赤ちゃんのうち3番目です
suddenly in that year
その年に突然
dropped to fourth place
4位に落ちた
fifth place
5位
sixth place
6位
Hope to catch up with diabetes to the seventh place soon
糖尿病を早く7位に追いつきたい
next
次
This is where we put the whole
ここに全体を置きます
last july
今年去年七月
rewrite the whole
全体を書き直す
you can see this
これを見ることができます
This is the case with increased locomotive maneuvers
これは、機関車の操縦が増加した場合に当てはまります。
next
次
In front, T1 to T4 are all doing life-saving.
前ではT1からT4まで全員が救命活動を行っています。
I will talk about some functional issues later
機能的な問題については後ほど説明します
Since then, almost all researches have focused on functional
それ以来、ほぼすべての研究は機能に焦点を当ててきました。
Efforts to improve these functions
これらの機能向上への取り組み
I might speak faster
もっと早く話せるかもしれない
Because this place is still full of deep
ここはまだまだディープな場所だから
next
次
So what is this called a concussion?
では、これは脳震盪と呼ばれるものでしょうか？
or mild traumatic brain injury
または軽度の外傷性脳損傷
That is to say, the unconscious time should not exceed 30 minutes.
つまり、意識を失っている時間は 30 分を超えてはなりません。
This is the definition of the US Department of Defense
これは米国国防総省の定義です
The same goes for its altered consciousness
変性意識についても同様です
no more than 20 hours
20時間以内
Then there is memory loss within 24 hours
その後24時間以内に記憶喪失になる
while scores are 13 to 15
スコアが 13 から 15 の間
The most important one is
最も重要なことは、
Mild traumatic brain injury is a CT scan
軽度の外傷性脳損傷はCTスキャンです
are all
全てです
can't see things can't see hurt
ものが見えない、傷が見えない
But although I can't see the damage
でもダメージは見えないけど
It still has sequelae, let me tell you
まだ後遺症が残っています、教えてください
next
次
Why does everyone attach so much importance to this
なぜみんなこれをそんなに重要視するのですか
Mild The S just now means serious
マイルド 先ほどの S は深刻を意味します
M means mild
Mはマイルドを意味します
He said
彼は言った
Nearly 20% of the soldiers
兵士の20％近くが
sent to iraq afghanistan
アフガニスタンのイラクに送られる
After coming back, they still have this symptom 20%
帰国後もこの症状が続く 20%
What about in the Marine Corps?
海兵隊ではどうですか？
This is somewhere in Afghanistan
ここはアフガニスタンのどこかです
92% of his injuries are not likely to be brain injuries.
彼の怪我の92％は脳損傷ではない可能性が高い。
Then what
じゃあ何
This armed vehicle
この武装車両は
there's no way or no way to
方法がない、または方法がない
This blast wave especially
特に今回の爆風は
low low frequency wave
低 low frequency 的wave
damage to the brain
脳へのダメージ
So it is very simple to say
ですから、言うのはとても簡単です
if you are a soldier
あなたが兵士なら
there's an explosion nearby
近くで爆発があります
you have never been hurt before
あなたはこれまで怪我をしたことがありません
But 60% of people still have this
しかし、60％の人はまだこれを持っています
mild brain injury
軽度の脳損傷
What if there were more than four times before?
以前に 4 回以上あった場合はどうなるでしょうか?
100% will have this symptom
100％この症状が出ます
Symptoms come out
症状が出てくる
so this
したがって、この
Go back to the American soldier
アメリカ兵の話に戻りましょう
very serious
非常に深刻な
So he asked several countries
そこで彼はいくつかの国に尋ねました。
Let's do it together and see what he said too
一緒にやってみよう、そして彼が何を言ったか見てみましょう
Which country has done the most research
最も多くの研究を行った国はどこですか
So we also join in this study
そこで私たちもこの研究に参加します
So for this mild brain trauma
この軽度の脳外傷については
In fact we also have many
実際、私たちにもたくさんあります
We're just different types of injuries
私たちは怪我の種類が違うだけです
But also very mild
しかし、非常にマイルドでもあります
Many have never seen a doctor at all.
医者に一度も診たことがない人もたくさんいます。
But he has many symptoms
しかし、彼には多くの症状があります
next
次
i forgot or forgot to tell this
これを忘れたのか、伝えるのを忘れたのか
why is the voice hoarse
なぜ声がかすれているのか
right no
そうです、いいえ
not me mild brain trauma
私ではありません 軽度の脳外傷
because I was
私がそうだったので
pushing hard hat
ヘルメットを押す
I remember that time
あの時のことを覚えています
The Director of Nursing is
看護部長は、
Yu Yumei Professor Yu
余玉美 余教授
And Lai Meishu, Professor Lai
そしてライ・メイシュ、ライ教授
two are government
2人は政府
He arranged a lot of speeches for me
彼は私のためにたくさんのスピーチを手配してくれました
what to talk about
何を話そうか
Kaohsiung Taichung Countryside
高雄・台中の田舎
Talk about everything Three Gorges
三峡のすべてについて話しましょう
There are hundreds of games
何百ものゲームがある
He just wants to push this hard hat
彼はただこのヘルメットを押したいだけなのです
I was a scholar at that time
当時私は学者でした
Scholar's speech is enough
学者の講演だけで十分
talk now no one will listen
今話しても誰も聞いてくれないよ
This official is useless
この役人は駄目だ
nothing works
何も機能しません
was a scholar
学者だった
So academics I talk about hard hats all day long
だから学者たちは一日中ヘルメットのことを話しているんだ
it's important very important
それは重要です非常に重要です
I always take that
私はいつもそれをとります
a preserved egg tofu
保存卵豆腐
Then put it on the ground and show them
それからそれを地面に置いて見せてください
Broken in a plastic bag
ビニール袋の中で壊れた
That's how it was done back then
当時はそうやってやってたんだな
Preserved egg tofu
保存卵豆腐
So talk every day for a long time
だから毎日長い時間話してください
Afterwards, the voice killed the teeth
その後、声が歯を殺しました
can't come back
戻れない
As long as there are too many lectures in the course, it will start to kill the itch
コース内の講義が多すぎると、かゆみがなくなり始めます
This is the sequelae
これが後遺症です
not a brain injury
脳損傷ではない
The main symptom is anemia red disorder
主な症状は貧血赤色障害です
Look at this MTBI poor red disorder
このMTBI不良赤色障害を見てください
Because of Nell's connection to the cerebellar concussion.
ネルと小脳脳震盪が関係しているため。
headache hearing loss tinnitus
頭痛 難聴 耳鳴り
or cognitive impairment
または認知障害
So far there is no good treatment
今のところ良い治療法はない
nothing good so far
今のところ良いことは何もない
next
次
So this is four countries in the world
つまり、これは世界の 4 か国です
Israel is also a country that often explodes
イスラエルはよく爆発する国でもある
Motor vehicle accidents in Taiwan
台湾での自動車事故
famous a lot serious
有名なかなり深刻な
Sweden is one that is equal to less
スウェーデンは同等以下の国です
it is the least harmed country in the world
それは世界で最も被害が少ない国です
So they are more like a country-by-country study
したがって、これらは国ごとの研究に似ています
All directions, I will pass quickly, the next one
全方位、すぐに通り過ぎます、次
The diagnostic tool next
次に診断ツール
Of course this patient must have
もちろん患者さんは必ず持っているはずです
Inclusion and exclusion mean
包含と除外の意味
Which ones can be in it? Others can’t. The next one
どれがそれに参加できますか? 他のものは参加できません。次のものが
Then this is the basic information, about 190 or so
それから、これが基本的な情報です、約 190 かそこら
Because of this why the charge is less
このため料金が安くなります
Because of this the first patient has to agree to the second
このため、最初の患者は 2 番目の患者に同意する必要があります。
Once he does these tests
彼がこれらのテストを行うと、
It's all harmless
それはすべて無害です
It's just a questionnaire, what an hour?
ただのアンケートですが、何時間ですか？
Everyone will still avoid it
それでもみんな避けるだろう
But some because doing it helps him
でも、そうすることが彼の助けになるからという理由もある
so he will participate
それで彼は参加するでしょう
the next one
次のもの
Then you can see why this happened
そうすれば、なぜこれが起こったのかがわかります
About 50% of car accidents now
現在、事故の約50％は
Others are falls or injuries
その他は転倒や怪我
next
次
Then we used 14 tables
次に、14 個のテーブルを使用しました
This is all countries in the world
これは世界のすべての国です
Four countries synchronized
4カ国が同期
Doing this four, it's four tables
これを 4 つ行うと 4 つのテーブルになります
The next one, I don't mention this
次はこれには触れません
What are the main symptoms we see
私たちが見られる主な症状は何ですか
These are just the thirty types I just mentioned
これらは先ほど述べた 30 種類にすぎません
Of the ten, the most common is dizziness
10のうち、最も一般的なのはめまいです
Dizziness, dizziness after a mild injury
めまい、軽い怪我の後のめまい
headache, sleep disturbance
頭痛、睡眠障害
Now more and more data prove that
現在、ますます多くのデータがそれを証明しています
Sleep disturbance linked to brain injury
睡眠障害は脳損傷と関連している
mildly cause
軽度の原因
memory impairment
記憶障害
And I can't concentrate
そして集中できない
These five are the most common
この 5 つが最も一般的です
This is the first accused stage
これが最初の告発段階です
When impromptu, the next
即興でやるなら、次は
After six stars, you are following it
星 6 つ以降はフォロー中です
or headache, the most common
または頭痛、最も一般的なもの
Dizziness, now it's a headache, just dizziness
めまい、今は頭痛、ただのめまい
Then memory impairment, turn it up a bit
それから記憶障害、少し上げてください
then follow this
それからこれに従ってください
can't concentrate
集中できない
and
と
sleep disorder
睡眠障害
next
次
Then let's see what if it's dizzy?
では、めまいがした場合はどうなるか見てみましょう。
There are a few forms I think this one I'll make soon
いくつかフォームがあるので、これは近いうちに作ってみようと思います
Avaka scale, Dhi, Y, Bd scale
Avaka スケール、Dhi、Y、Bd スケール
These are all able to detect this
これらはすべてこれを検出できます
Dissidence is dizziness
不和はめまいだ
Headache is one
頭痛もその一つ
Anxious VAI scale helps
不安な VAI スケールが役立ちます
next
次
What about sleep disorders?
睡眠障害についてはどうですか？
This VAI BDI
この VAI BDI
Here are some tables of depression
ここにうつ病のいくつかの表があります
Also the Digitspan of this memory
このメモリの桁数も
These few are related to the next one
これらのいくつかは次のものに関連しています
What about memory? These two
メモリはどうですか? この 2 つ
DHI and Digitspan
DHI とディジットスパン
these two
この二つ
So now many scales can be measured
これで、多くのスケールが測定できるようになりました
some very mild symptoms
いくつかの非常に軽い症状
This is what several of our countries are doing together.
これは私たちのいくつかの国が協力して行っていることです。
Then I also took these medicines at the same time
それから私はこれらの薬も同時に服用しました
Here are some medicines
ここにいくつかの薬があります
Well, we're almost in sync and venting too
まあ、私たちもほぼ同期して発散しています
The previous medicine helped with dizziness
以前の薬はめまいに効果がありました
Topamax was originally an antiepileptic drug
トパマックスはもともと抗てんかん薬でした
Helpful for this depression
このうつ病に役立つ
Serenna is helpful to designus
セレナはデザナスに役立つ
So take it slow
だからゆっくりしてください
Because there was no special medicine on the mild head part
軽度の頭部には特別な薬がなかったので
everyone has been looking for
みんなが探していた
Find out if there is any medicine that can help these symptoms
このような症状に効く薬がないか調べる
especially long-term symptoms
特に長期にわたる症状
next
次
The second is to use the functional
2 つ目は、関数型を使用することです。
Resonance scan
共鳴スキャン
functional MRI to test memory
記憶を検査する機能的MRI
this is also very important
これも非常に重要です
next
次
For example, this is called
たとえば、これは次のように呼ばれます
is walking memory
歩く記憶です
It's you who saw these faces
この顔を見たのはあなたです
which one have you seen
どれを見ましたか
just think about it
考えてみてください
seen this
これを見た
He will test you again when you are using your brain
あなたが頭を使っているとき、彼はあなたをもう一度テストします
Test your activity
アクティビティをテストする
next
次
Then this is one back
それからこれはもう一つです
Just look at a number and then look at it for the first time
数字を見て、初めて見てみる
Whichever ones you have seen, you can point them out
あなたが見たものであれば、それらを指摘することができます
After seeing this, press your hand
これを見て手を押してください
Then you are called walk in memory
そうすればあなたはウォーク・イン・メモリーと呼ばれます
one back
1つ戻る
two back is
2バックは
I have to remember more
もっと覚えておかなければいけない
How did you compare to last time?
前回と比べてどうでしたか？
three back is
スリーバックは
How much do you remember from the last time
前回のことをどのくらい覚えていますか
wow he's about to think
うわー、彼は考えるだろう
Think about this kind of one back two back three back
こんな感じの1バック2バック3バックを考えてみましょう
next
次
then you can see
そうすればわかります
one back normal
1バックノーマル
two back three back
2バック 3バック
he uses more brainpower
彼はより多くの知力を使う
But this wounded person
でもこの傷ついた人は
he is bad
彼は悪いです
he's all bad
彼は全部悪いよ
poor memory
記憶力が悪い
next
次
then you too
それならあなたも
if you cut it off
それを切り取ったら
You can see the wounded people almost
負傷者がほとんど見えます
When it comes to two back three back
２バック３バックになると
he can't use anything
彼は何も使えない
next
次
Then this is after progress
では、これは進歩後です
this is the initial stage
これは初期段階です
When I was first injured
初めて怪我をしたとき
you can see this
これを見ることができます
2BG reduced to 1BG
2BGが1BGに減少
Or 3BG reduced to 2BG
または 3BG が 2BG に減ります
are relatively poor
比較的貧しい
but
しかし
about 6 weeks later
約6週間後
You can see it's coming back a lot
かなり戻ってきているのがわかります
next
次
So
それで
This is called Rest in state
これを休息状態といいます
functional MRI
機能的MRI
this one has to close the eyes
これは目を閉じなければなりません
can't think about anything
何も考えられない
This is pretty difficult
これはかなり難しいです
and then can't fall asleep
そして眠れなくなる
It's also very complicated to do this
これを行うのも非常に複雑です
It's been a long time
おひさしぶりですね
next
次
all the world does is see
世界は見ることだけをしている
what is this looking at
これは何を見ているのですか
connectivity
接続性
In fact, the mind of the brain
実は脳の心は
are all interrelated
相互接続されている
It's all interconnected
すべては相互につながっている
There are about 8 places in the world that do it
世界にはそれをやっている場所が約8か所あります
I won't mention this
これについては言及しません
next
次
We did about these 4 places
この4か所くらいやりました
You can see this is normal
これが正常であることがわかります
Both sides are pretty good. Connectivity is not bad.
双方ともかなり良好で、接続性も悪くありません。
Connectivity of two brains after injury
損傷後の2つの脳の接続
Activity Connectivity is bad
アクティビティの接続が悪い
next
次
this is the same
これも同じです
Another place with AC
エアコンのある別の場所
This will get worse
これはさらに悪化します
next
次
This IPL is getting worse
この IPL は悪化しています
this is getting worse
これは悪化しています
next
次
This IPC has also become worse.
このIPCも悪化しています。
So the whole thing looks like this is pretty obvious for
全体としては、これは非常に明白であるように見えます
functional connectivity
機能的な接続
All in Resident State Network
すべて居住州ネットワーク内にあります
It's obviously getting worse
明らかに悪化してる
next
次
that's all we want to say
私たちが言いたいのはそれだけです
took a lot of medicine
たくさんの薬を飲みました
Some help some not necessarily
必ずしも役立つわけではないものもある
Most recent from 2008
最新のものは 2008 年から
I am reporting by the way
ところで報告してます
It's Felici
フェリシだよ
Report a rather shocking statement that
というかなり衝撃的な発言を報告する
For this use this TTCS
これには、この TTCS を使用します
TTCS
TTCS
So how about stimulating the brain?
では、脳を刺激してみてはどうでしょうか？
Find out about this R-CIMER
このR-CIMERについて調べる
Or is there a
それともありますか
Motor neuritis can help
運動神経炎が役に立つ
then this doesn't hurt
それは痛くない
no harm so far
今のところ害はありません
So we also made a few
それで私たちもいくつか作りました
next
次
see if it helps
役立つかどうか見てください
Just after the injury
怪我の直後
You'll see it compared with
と比べるとわかります
scattered
散らばっている
This activity suddenly dissipates
この活動は突然消えました
It seems to be better after finishing
終わった後は良くなった気がする
next
次
this is the same
これも同じです
This patient is obviously
この患者さんは明らかに
Sometimes his memory improves
時々彼の記憶力が改善する
But this one hasn't
しかし、これはそうではありません
very mature
とても成熟した
just everyone now
今はみんなだけ
Only started coming out after 2008
2008年以降に出始めたばかり
just use normal
普通に使ってください
very light
とても軽い
very small stimulus
非常に小さな刺激
next
次
I won't mention this
これについては言及しません
then in addition
それからさらに
the third is
3つ目は
What I want to tell you is
私があなたに伝えたいのは、
It is very simple called BioMarker
BioMarkerと呼ばれる非常にシンプルです
BioMarker is
バイオマーカーは
after you get hurt
怪我をした後
There must be a component in the blood or spinal cord that will try out
血液または脊髄には、それを試みる成分が存在するに違いありません。
will rise
上がるだろう
Then we are looking for the most ideal BioMarker
そして、最も理想的なバイオマーカーを探します
What is called BioMarker?
バイオマーカーとは何ですか?
This biomarker is now the world's
このバイオマーカーは現在、世界の
This Vice President Chen is in prison
この陳副総統は刑務所にいます
But it's more complicated in the brain
しかし、脳の中ではもっと複雑です
especially after traumatic brain injury
特に外傷性脳損傷後
next
次
then we are looking for
それから私たちは探しています
This must be the most ideal BioMarker
これが最も理想的なバイオマーカーでしょう
must be easy to get
簡単に手に入るはずです
As far as the patient is concerned, don't suffer too much
患者さんに関する限り、あまり苦しみすぎないでください
Put a tube in your head to get it
頭にチューブを入れて取得します
it doesn't make sense
意味がありません
So normal blood can be seen
正常な血液が見えるようになる
then it has diagnostic value
診断上の価値がある
It is also helpful for the queen
女王様にとっても助かります
From BioMarker you can see that
BioMarker からは次のことがわかります。
what will happen to this patient
この患者はどうなるのか
hope so
そう願っています
Will the memory come back?
記憶は戻るのでしょうか？
what will happen
何が起こるか
Will motor function return?
運動機能は戻りますか？
Then there is a therapeutic effect
そうすれば治療効果もある
this is very important
これはとても重要です
the most important thing
一番大切なもの
it can follow its severity
重症度に従うことができる
or the progression of its time
あるいはその時代の進歩
can show its composition
その構成を示すことができる
say it's progressing
進んでいると言う
We saw that Marker come down
マーカーが降りてくるのが見えました
I knew what would happen to this patient
この患者に何が起こるか分かっていた
next
次
So we have a clinical pathway
つまりクリニカルパスがあるのです
Decision Tree
デシジョンツリー
Decision Tree means
デシジョンツリーの意味
My wine room has a slight
私のワインルームにはわずかな
10% serious
10% 深刻
Then some cut and some don't
それから、切れるものと切れないものがあります
The last 95% live
最後の 95% はライブです
1% of these living people are vegetative
生きている人間の 1% は植物人間です
4% are severely disabled
4%が重度障害者
7%
７％
then 80%
その後80%
3% recovery
3%回復
what about this
これはどうですか
Let's look at his cognitive function at the end
最後に彼の認知機能を見てみましょう
psychological function
心理的機能
or physiological functions, etc.
あるいは生理機能など​​。
What about from this process?
このプロセスからはどうでしょうか？
We can use BioMarker to analyze him
BioMarker を使用して彼を分析できます
next
次
This is what we are doing now
これが私たちが今やっていることです
We report a lot of BioMarkers all over the world
私たちは世界中の多くのバイオマーカーを報告しています
that this
これは
We are more commonly used is S100B
私たちがよく使うのはS100Bです
GFAP's NSE and Apple E
GFAPのNSEとApple E
next
次
so recently
とても最近
we found a
私たちは見つけました
ETK
ETK
I don’t think I need to talk about this ETK anymore
このETKについてはもう話す必要はないと思います
then this
それからこれ
right
右
A lot of what we want is met
私たちが望むものの多くは満たされています
next
次
I don't think I need the next one
次は要らないと思う
for example
例えば
he can control
彼はコントロールできる
injured on the right
右側を負傷
that will make it stronger
それが強くなるだろう
Gao Qiang on the right hand
右手にガオ・チャン
Then Impact 2
次にインパクト2
Heavier damage is deeper
ダメージが大きいほど深い
this is the same
これも同じです
it can be divided left and right
左右に分割可能です
next
次
even it can
それさえできる
It knows both weight and strength
重さと強さの両方を知っています
Same as this S100 X10
これと同じ S100 X10
Of course there is one, but it's not so clear
もちろんありますが、それほど明確ではありません
also a little
それも少し
then even in
それからでも
When Impact is heavy
衝撃が大きいとき
When the strength is greater
強度が大きくなると
it is heavier
それは重いです
Then look at its timing, timing
それからそのタイミングを見てください、タイミング
time this is GFAP
今度はGFAPです
This is Acting
これは演技です
then look at this
それからこれを見てください
One hour Three hours Six hours One day Ten days
1時間 3時間 6時間 1日 10日間
Then what
じゃあ何
When the brain swelling starts to disappear
脳の腫れが消え始めるとき
it just falls
それはただ落ちるだけです
so for this time
それで今回は
Timing Severity
タイミングの重大度
help in every way
あらゆる面で助けてください
next
次
so what do we think
それで私たちはどう思いますか
this may be a
これはかもしれない
Effective BioMarker
効果的なバイオマーカー
It this Rapid Change
この急速な変化
There are T-Shows Organization Specific
組織固有の T ショーがあります
have a diagnosis
診断を受けてください
In addition
加えて
it can know the severity
重症度を知ることができる
And Time Course
そして時間の経過
and easy to get
そして簡単に手に入る
So maybe a Candidate BioMarker
おそらくバイオマーカー候補
TBI
外傷性脳損傷
This is the direction we are trying to find
これが私たちが見つけようとしている方向性です
next
次
So
それで
new drug development
新薬開発
Of course, the development of this new drug has nothing to do with BioMarker
もちろん、この新薬の開発はBioMarkerとは何の関係もありません
very relevant
非常に関連性の高い
With the BioMarker just mentioned
先ほど述べた BioMarker を使用すると、
next
次
Then this is our cooperation with Academia Sinica
それから、これは中央研究院との協力です。
us
私たち
This one from Beijing Medical University
これは北京医科大学のものです
School of Pharmacy cooperates with Academia Sinica
薬学部は中央研究院と協力しています
Scream comes out a lot
悲鳴がよく出る
Red are neuroprotective drugs
赤は神経保護薬です
Then we chose a program called Emo-Dim
次に、Emo-Dim というプログラムを選択しました。
Emo-Dim
エモディム
next
次
then this is
それならこれは
This is an emodin
これはエモジンです
But a Compound
しかし、化合物
next
次
Then we start from the first day
それでは初日からスタートです
just give him the next one
彼に次のものを与えてください
You can see that this is the taste of water maize
これが水トウモロコシの味であることがわかります
A test on the memory of mice
マウスの記憶力のテスト
It can be seen that this is injured and it will become like this
これが傷つくとこうなるのが目に見えてます
this is
これは
I used this emodim and it seems to be helpful
この emodim を使用しましたが、役に立ちそうです
Of course in the end with
もちろん最後には
Even better than this sham
この偽物よりもさらに良い
is to control
コントロールすることです
You can see in this process
この過程でわかります
emodim
エモディム
ETK, GFAP, Connecting
ETK、GFAP、接続中
These indicators are very obvious
これらの指標は非常に明白です
lower than the original
オリジナルより低い
Especially ETK with obvious
特に明らかなETK
I think this is from days
これは数日前からだと思います
fourth day, seventh day
4日目、7日目
I think
私が思うに
It is of course better to look at several indicators at the same time
もちろん、複数の指標を同時に見る方が良いです
This bio mark is better
このバイオマークの方が良い
But this proves that the medicine
しかし、これは薬が
to this
これに
Then the protection function is there
それから保護機能があります
So now let's develop BioMarker first
それでは、まず BioMarker を開発しましょう
Then see the effect of this medicine
それではこの薬の効果を見てみましょう
This is also a good direction
これも良い方向ですね
next
次
So we also think that ETK is
したがって、ETK は
With this severity is a good BioMarker
この重症度であれば、優れたバイオマーカーです
In addition this EmoDIM is
なお、このEmoDIMは
Helpful for this too
これにも役立ちます
next
次
so probably
だからおそらく
These are the ones we are doing research on
これらは私たちが研究しているものです
And we still have a few
そしてまだいくつかあります
The result hasn't come out yet
結果はまだ出ていません
just a few sleep cycles
ほんの数回の睡眠サイクル
Called Sercadium Regen
セルカジウム・リジェネと呼ばれる
There are also some genetic tests
遺伝子検査もある
Genetic testing probably won't make sense to everyone
遺伝子検査はおそらく誰にとっても意味をなさないでしょう
But in this gene
しかし、この遺伝子には
Many of them also affect the prognosis of patients
それらの多くは患者の予後に影響を与えます
this is
これは
the whole process
プロセス全体
what about the future
将来はどうですか
next
次
We'll probably all be doing this in the future
おそらく将来的には全員がこれを行うことになるでしょう
This is what we just saw
これが私たちが今見たものです
They are all doing life-saving work
彼らは皆、命を救う仕事をしています
Then the future is us
そうすれば未来は我々だ
it keeps falling
落ちてきた
keep falling
落ち続ける
In the future, it is to improve the function
今後は機能向上を目指します
At the same time the next one
同時に次も
then what to do at the same time
じゃあ同時に何をすればいいのか
economic benefit
経済的利益
Then this is Chen
それではチェンです
Vice President Chen
陳副総統
He hosted a program called BioSignature
彼は BioSignature というプログラムを主催しました
The most important thing here is the BioMarkers
ここで最も重要なことはバイオマーカーです
add this
これを追加
Cost-effectiveness
費用対効果
If it is possible to put this
これを載せて頂ければ
fell down
落ちた
to this
これに
Finance can also help
金融も役に立つ
To this Cost Effective
ここまで費用対効果が高い
that's even better
それはさらに良いです
what about the future, of course i think about this
将来はどうなるか、もちろんそれについては考えます
direction is very good
方向性はとても良いです
next
次
let's look at this
これを見てみましょう
whole traumatic brain
外傷性脳全体
Health insurance data files
健康保険データファイル
you can see
見ることができます
Our patients have been decreasing just like what we did just now
さっきと同じように患者さんが減ってきました
has been decreasing
減少している
But for the next one, his fee will continue to be high
しかし、次回の報酬は引き続き高額になるだろう
So this is also the direction we have to work hard
これも私たちが頑張らなければならない方向です
next
次
Then this is also a patient in the outpatient clinic.
それから、これも外来の患者さんです。
That probably cost us a lot.
おそらくそれは多大な費用がかかったでしょう。
So this is also a heavy burden for the country
これも国にとっては大きな負担です
Maybe we can specialize in patients with these sequelae
これらの後遺症を持つ患者を専門にできるかもしれない
also have a great influence
も大きな影響力を持っています
next
次
so i think the future
だから私は未来を考える
we will continue to do some
私たちはいくつかのことを続けます
to this BioSignature
このバイオシグネチャーに
What I was talking about just now is
私が今話していたのは、
BioMaker plus a study of Cos effective
BioMaker と Cos 効果の研究
Then continuing this will be of greater help to mankind.
そうすれば、これを継続することが人類にとってより大きな助けとなるでしょう。
next
次
then this is
それならこれは
This is Chen Yun
チェンユンです
Chen Yun is the team led by Lea Hardware
Chen Yun は Lea Hardware が率いるチームです
next
次
so
それで
The whole conclusion is that
全体の結論は次のとおりです
what about our research
私たちの研究はどうですか
Do it all the way from T1, T2, T3, T4
T1、T2、T3、T4 からずっと実行します。
Finally, we improved the function
ついに機能改善しました
In addition to saving lives
命を救うことに加えて
Finally, we still need to improve this function, the next one
最後に、この機能はまだ改善する必要があります。次の機能です。
We are currently working on many more
現在、さらに多くのことに取り組んでいます
This is also a clinical trial
これも臨床試験です
This is made by a manor
これは荘園が作ったものです
He uses this in the neurological function of the flying belly
彼はこれを飛行腹部の神経機能に利用しています。
very good on animals
動物に対してとても良い
So this we will study in the future
したがって、これは今後勉強します
Is it helpful to people, the next one
人の役に立ちますか、次は
and we will continue
そして私たちは続けます
With the US National Institutes of Health
米国国立衛生研究所との協力
And some of our institutions in Taiwan
台湾のいくつかの機関では
Many institutions have eight topics in progress
多くの機関が 8 つのトピックを進行中です
In fact, probably this
実はこれ、おそらく、
Also are some nerve restoration NUROProtective
NUROProtective による神経修復も行われます。
How to do nerve protection
神経保護の方法
next
次
This is what we are grateful to the team
これは私たちがチームに感謝していることです
There are also various Supporting Agents
サポートエージェントも充実
So I guess the whole process goes like this
全体のプロセスは次のようになると思います
This is a lot
これはたくさんあります
a hard hat push
ヘルメットプッシュ
In fact, it is supported by many studies
実際、それは多くの研究によって裏付けられています
So research may be a
したがって、研究は
A very important process of a legislation
法律制定の非常に重要なプロセス
I want to simply report to here
ここに簡単に報告したいと思います
Thanks
ありがとう
We thank the old director
老監督に感謝します
give us this wonderful speech
この素晴らしいスピーチを私たちに聞かせてください
What to say from foreign research
海外の研究から言えること
pushed until legislation
法案化まで延期された
and how to make his voice affected
そして彼の声に影響を与える方法
Then everyone's lifespan can be reduced
そうすれば全員の寿命が縮む可能性がある
In fact, you can see
実際、ご覧のとおり
Now foreign businessmen have to pay gold coins to the government
現在、外国人ビジネスマンは政府に金貨を支払わなければならない
also quite a lot
それもかなりたくさん
I really appreciate the care he has done for the health of our people.
私は彼が私たちの人々の健康のために行ってくれた配慮に本当に感謝しています。
that now
那現在
After the Soviet Party finished speaking, I don’t know if you have any questions and would like to ask for leave. Please come here.
ソ連側の発言が終わりましたら、何かご質問があるかどうかわかりませんが、お休みをいただきたいと思いますので、こちらへお越しください。
I want to thank the Soviet Party today
今日はソ連に感謝したいと思います
give us then
それなら私たちにください
That's more information
それは詳しい情報です
I want to ask the Soviet Party
ソ連に聞きたい
The emphasis is on the brain, but you didn’t mention traditional Chinese medicine in your speech just now.
それは脳を強調していますね、先ほどの講演では漢方薬について触れていませんでしたね
that of Chinese medicine
漢方薬のこと
TCM assistance in this regard
この点に関するTCMの支援
is that
それは？
please that
それをお願いします
Then explain it, okay?
それから説明してください、いいですか？
thanks for that
それはありがとう
TCM we probably
中国医学はおそらく
more importantly
さらに重要なことには
From the research of traditional Chinese medicine, the emodin mentioned just now
伝統的な中国医学の研究から、今言及したエモジン
So
それで
Of course, the way of Chinese medicine is general
もちろん中医学のやり方は一般的ですが、
more acute
より深刻な
Or in Western medicine more
あるいは西洋医学ではもっと
We don't have a deep understanding of traditional Chinese medicine.
私たちは伝統的な中国医学については深く理解していません。
Generally, we cooperate with traditional Chinese medicine
基本的には漢方薬と連携しております
all in Chinese medicine
すべては中国医学で
Aspects of these restorations to memory function
記憶機能に関するこれらの修復の側面
probably like this
おそらくこんな感じ
Ask Director Qiu
邱監督に聞く
Today I am very convinced to hear the director's lecture
今日院長の講演を聞いてとても納得しました
Because I used to crash
昔クラッシュしてたから
I mean the motorcycle fell off
つまりバイクが落ちた
That moment was almost a few seconds
その瞬間はほんの数秒だった
not at all for a few seconds
数秒間はまったくそうではなかった
i.e. completely blank
つまり完全に空白
then wake up
それから目を覚ます
I just feel my head is so heavy
ただ頭がとても重い気がする
At that time, it was very heavy to wear a hard hat.
当時、ヘルメットをかぶるのはとても重かったです。
that until today
それは今日まで
but at that time
しかしその時は
I don't feel like I didn't go to the hospital
病院に行かなかった気がする
Then you just mentioned that this has
それから、あなたは今、これはこうなったと言いました
just say how much
いくらか言ってください
After 30%, it will be easier to change the time card
30%を超えると元号証明書の変更が容易になります
I've been doing this for almost a few years
ほぼ数年間これをやっています
then you pass
それならあなたは合格します
almost ten years
ほぼ10年
Cleared
クリア済み
Will there be sequelae in the future?
将来的に後遺症は残るのでしょうか？
It all happened a year or two later, some will happen again
すべては1年か2年後に起こりましたが、いくつかは再び起こるでしょう
But after a while it rarely happens again
しかし、しばらくすると再発することはほとんどありません
rare
レア
That is to say later
つまり後ほど
Is memory affected
記憶力に影響があるのか
my memory is not very good
私の記憶力はあまり良くありません
but not serious
でも深刻ではない
That is to say, it is still possible to read
つまり、まだ読むことは可能です
can still learn
まだ学ぶことができます
That is not bad
それは悪くない
you have passed
あなたは合格しました
It should be passed
渡されるべきだ
Really will not advance the times in the future
本当にこれからも時代は進まない
rare
レア
In our watch rarely happens again
私たちの時計では再発することはめったにありません
so
それで
Some people have more than a year
1年以上持つ人もいる
Very good
とても良い
thank you so much
太感謝了
Thank you, Mr. Su, thank you
スーさん、ありがとう、ありがとう
an intro to me just forgot
忘れてたイントロ
Our Professor Jiang Yongsai
私たちの姜永斎教授
He is actually the soul of this study
実は彼こそがこの研究の魂なのです
Then when I go to Su, he is doing it now.
それでスーのところに行くと、今やってるんです。
Thanks
ありがとう
Lord, you just mentioned
主よ、あなたは今言いました
about alheimer's disease
アルハイマー病について
Then this is now the biggest threat to our people
そうなると、これは今、我が国の人々にとって最大の脅威となっています
Now the age of bottle gold has been increasing
ボトルゴールドの時代はさらに進んでいます
Does your field cover this part?
あなたの分野はこの部分をカバーしていますか？
we are surgeons
私たちは外科医です
Most of that is done by physicians
そのほとんどは医師によって行われます
but this
しかしこれは
his current base
彼の現在の拠点
more and more clear
ますます明確になる
But still not completely Clear
でもまだ完全にクリアではない
but it is becoming clearer
しかし、それは明らかになりつつあります
Or I just had a lot of it
それともただたくさん持っていただけなのか
BioMarket has something to do with that
BioMarketはそれと関係があります
Maybe Director Jiang has no idea about this
もしかしたら江監督はこのことを知らないのかもしれない
What comment does R-Type have?
R-TYPEのコメントは？
Just according to the latest statistics
最新の統計によると
That is to say, to create a
つまり、
The origin of disability
障害の起源
old trauma is caused
昔のトラウマが原因で
one issued by early tibet
初期チベットで発行されたもの
So basically speaking, the quality that the teacher likes
基本的に言えば、教師が好む品質
better not get hurt
怪我しないほうがいいよ
another one
もう一つ
In addition to talking about the severity of his injuries
怪我の重さについて話すことに加えて、
We are still in the number
私たちはまだ数の中にいます
more times
複数回
Of course the brain will be
もちろん脳もそうなるだろう
means we bad chance
チャンスが悪いという意味です
In fact, we used to have neurology diseases
実際、私たちはかつて神経疾患を患っていました
But he suffered from trauma
しかし彼はトラウマを抱えていた
Now it is getting more and more attention all over the world
今、世界中でますます注目を集めています
but it's normal now
でも今は普通だよ
our this
私たちのこれ
The main forest six community industry will encounter this problem
主力の林六コミュニティ産業はこの問題に直面するだろう
old age
老齢
all have this phenomenon
みんなこの現象あるよ
sorry
ごめん
After joining
クラスに参加してから
I just raised my hand and didn't get clicked
手を挙げただけでクリックされませんでした
I'm at a community college promoting
私はコミュニティカレッジでプロモーションを行っています
Lin Jingtang, a teacher of memory promotion and prevention, gave a speech
記憶促進と予防の教師である林京棠氏が講演した
i have two questions for the dean
学部長に二つ質問があります
The first one is that just now we talked about
1つ目は、今お話ししたことです。
during that treatment
その治療中に
will do this
これをします
farming or raising
農業または飼育
But from the inside of the antioxidant machine inside Professor Lin Tiansong
しかし、リン・ティアンソン教授の体内の抗酸化マシンの内部から
he mentioned a very important thing
彼はとても重要なことを言いました
He said that in the process of first aid, especially in the ambulance
彼は、応急処置の過程、特に救急車の中で、と述べた。
He often gives an injection of that SOD first
彼は最初にその SOD を注射することがよくあります
The kind of potion that resists oxidation or polarizes beauty
酸化を防ぎ、美しさを極化させる一種の薬
It means that after the epidemic prevention, his future brain
それは、疫病予防の後、彼の将来の脳が
even if rescued
たとえ救出されたとしても
But his cognitive function will be impaired
しかし認知機能は障害されるだろう
Because we all need to know that raising the brain is the biggest attack
脳を育てることが最大の攻撃であることを私たち全員が知る必要があるからです
Because the oxidizer is
酸化剤があるので、
That brain attack is the biggest
あの脳攻撃が一番大きい
this is the second question
これは 2 番目の質問です
The second question I have
2番目の質問です
During the teaching process, one of the students was also injured by a motorcycle
授業中に生徒の一人もバイクに轢かれて負傷した
then he comes
それから彼は来ます
When he told me about his condition, my master had already
主人が私に病状を話したとき、すでに主人は
because of how he is i listen to him
彼の様子だから私は彼の言うことを聞く
Ask him to explain how he got hurt first
まず彼にどのように怪我をしたのか説明してもらいます
estimate a little
少し見積もる
You are probably missing the back of your head
あなたはおそらく後頭部が欠けているでしょう
because he has a symptom
彼には症状があるから
that is
あれは
May have been touched all night
一晩中触られていたかもしれない
cortical nerve
皮質神経
Is there a large area of ​​local fusion or something?
ローカルフュージョンか何かの広いエリアはありますか？
I don't know
わからない
But he produced a phenomenon
しかし彼はある現象を引き起こした
He just creates some mutual
彼はただ相互作用を生み出すだけです
or Internet
またはインターネット
In other words, I see Su Zhanglin now
言い換えれば、私は今蘇張林を見ています
Standing over there is not only one
あそこに立っているのは一人だけではない
maybe three maybe five
たぶん3つかもしれない、5つかもしれない
while standing there
そこに立っている間
Then he went to the capital department
それから彼は首都局に行きました
each north each
各北部各
Because we live in Taoyuan
私たちは桃園に住んでいるから
Hospitals in Taoyuan in the northern regions have seen
北部地域の桃園市の病院では、
Then the capital division
次に資本分割
The ophthalmologist also went to see the workers are normal
眼科医も行って作業員は正常だった
but can't explain
でも説明できない
It's just that there is no way to treat it.
ただ、治療する方法がないというだけです。
I use one I know of called
私が知っている名前のものを使用しています
Jeffson's Nice Law
ジェフソンの素敵な法則
tell him to watch the moon at night
彼に夜月を見るように言います
Then use this method to host
次に、このメソッドを使用してホストします
Let me see if the image can overlap again
もう一度画像を重ねられるかどうか見てみましょう
I don't know about that
それについては知りません
This medical base of that brain turns up
その脳の医学的基盤が判明
Is there anything I can do to increase my knowledge
知識を増やすために何かできることはありますか
the most important one
最も重要なもの
That is, the occupational therapy component
つまり、作業療法の要素です。
to this part of the brain
脳のこの部分に
rarely treated
めったに治療されない
I don't know if the Director can help in this regard
ディレクターがこの点に関して協力できるかどうかはわかりません
give me some guidance thanks
教えてください、ありがとう
This abdomen produced by treatment
治療によって生み出されたこのお腹
usually
いつもの
because of some eye movement or
何らかの目の動きのせいで、または
external nerve injury
外神経損傷
or some kind of nerve injury
または何らかの神経損傷
that would have a negative impact
それはマイナスの影響を与えるだろう
This long time see we long time see
この長い間見て、私たちは長い間見て
Another phenomenon is
もう一つの現象は、
epileptic cancer
てんかんがん
Sadistic epilepsy, it produces hallucinations
サディスティックてんかん、幻覚を引き起こす
or these
またはこれら
It's a brain injury long enough to see
目に見えるほど長い脳損傷だ
but i didn't see it
でも見えなかった
I don't know what this is
これが何なのか分かりません
what kind of sobriety
どういう禁酒なのか
Then generally this
それから、一般的にはこれ
Causes can be found in most cases
腹部のほとんどの原因は見つかります
Doing a lot of testing can find
多くのテストを行うことで発見できるのは、
Sometimes even use brainwaves
場合によっては脳波も使う
look inside the brain
脳の中を見てみる
Is there any abnormal discharge
異常な分泌物はありませんか
Sometimes this abnormal discharge is
時々、この異常放電は、
saw this for a while
しばらくこれを見ました
but sometimes it doesn't
でもそうでないこともある
See if it's straight or long like this
このようにまっすぐか長いかを確認してください
So if there is a function
それで機能があれば
That 346 nerve injury
346神経損傷
that will also
それもまた
Also in the brainstem
脳幹にも
Sometimes the brainstem
時には脳幹
We're like at EW Nuclear
私たちはEW Nuclearにいるようなものです
that will also
それもまた
That's where our third pair came out
そこで3番目のペアが登場しました
Like the brainstem or where it comes out
脳幹とかそれが出る場所とか
where the primitive nucleus
原始核はどこにあるのか
Injury can also produce this phenomenon
怪我もこの現象を引き起こす可能性があります
So there are quite a few reasons for it
だからそれにはかなりの理由がある
But the most important thing is to find out and find a way to treat it.
しかし、最も重要なことは、それを調べて治療する方法を見つけることです。
Also the second is
また2つ目は、
The problem with SODs
SOD的問題
I'll start with the neurorehabilitation
ニューロリハビリテーションから始めます
This is where Taiwan should work hard
ここは台湾が頑張るべきところだ
Because I was 30 or 20 years ago
30年か20年前だから
probably soon
現在大概快
I forget my age now
今では自分の年齢を忘れています
bad memory
悪い記憶
When I was in America about 20 years ago
20年ほど前にアメリカにいた頃
i see its rehab center
リハビリセンターが見えます
Very serious about brain sores
對腦瘡傷非常重視
Wow, all kinds of mental rehabilitation
うわー、あらゆる種類の精神的リハビリテーション
Function is neuro psychology
機能は神経心理学です
rehab rotation center
リハビリローテーションセンター
I am back in Taiwan and it is strange that our rehab is very simple
私は台湾に戻ってきましたが、私たちのリハビリがとてもシンプルなのが不思議です
I am not dividing any brain or anything
私は脳などを分割していません
But in that place whether you're in Texas
でも、あなたがテキサスにいるかどうかに関係なく、その場所では
I see this brain rehab center everywhere in Pittsburgh
ピッツバーグのいたるところでこの脳リハビリセンターを見かけます
And a lot of people inside are once
そして、内部にいる多くの人がかつては
Two, three or four people sit inside
中には2人か3人か4人が座ります
So now there are several big centers in Taiwan
現在、台湾には大きなセンターがいくつかあります
have already started, so the rehabilitation of the nerves
すでに始まっているので神経のリハビリテーション
we really have a lot of room to strengthen
私たちには本当に強化する余地がたくさんある
I want to thank you for specifically reminding this
このことを具体的に思い出させてくれてありがとうと言いたい
This is very important for Taiwan
これは台湾にとって非常に重要です
is this good
これでいいですか
so you can see it's not tv lately
最近はテレビじゃないのがわかりますね
have seen one
一つ見たことがあります
This congressman was shot or what?
この議員は撃たれたのか、それとも何なのか？
Afterwards, the skin returned to normal
その後、肌は正常に戻りました
This is a very good function
これはとても良い機能です
or mental rehabilitation
あるいは精神的なリハビリテーション
Mental rehabilitation is doing very well.
精神面のリハビリも順調に進んでいます。
there is a way to do this
これを行う方法があります
I think you are very discerning
あなたはとても洞察力があると思います
As for this SOD in
このSODは
If you go in, call him
入ったら彼に電話してください
This is generally not yet
これは一般的にはまだです
Inside GiLine
ギライン内
We said why do GiLine
なぜGiLineをするのかと言った
the whole world or the whole country
世界全体または国全体
universally acknowledged fact
広く認められた事実
so maybe it helps
それで役立つかもしれない
But if it's still in the research stage
ただし、まだ研究段階であれば、
We don't put in GiLine
ギラインは入れてません
Do not put in GiLine
ギラインは入れないでください
you don't have to do it routinely
定期的に行う必要はありません
But sometimes you can upgrade
ただし、アップグレードできる場合もあります
Whole trial if patient agrees
患者が同意すれば治験全体
Can use
使える
this i think this is
これは私はこれだと思う
The current measures of this
この現状の対策としては、
GiLine not yet
GiLineはまだです
sorry
ごめん
Of course the team leader
もちろんチームリーダーも
The leader compliments me like this
リーダーがこんな風に褒めてくれました
i can't
私はできません
I need to change my major a little bit
専攻を少し変える必要がある
don't report
報告しないでください
That is to say, in fact, after ten years in Taiwan,
つまり、実際、台湾に10年間住んだ後、
The dementia or cognitive impairment
認知症または認知障害
Even cognitive degeneration affects behavior
認知機能の低下さえも行動に影響を与える
Then this kind of thing that affects the family
そうすると家族に影響を及ぼすようなことになる
i have dealt with a lot
私はたくさんのことに対処しました
So I feel that the future of Taiwan is really scary
だから台湾の将来は本当に怖いと思う
The streets are full of old people who are afraid
街は恐怖を感じている老人でいっぱいです
And I don't even know where my home is
そして、自分の家がどこにあるのかさえ知りません
this is too much
これは、やりすぎ
the point is to say
ポイントは言うことです
because in Europe
なぜならヨーロッパでは
Now in Brain Science Education
現在は脳科学教育に携わっている
not wrong
間違っていません
This piece of adult education on the education of the brain
脳の教育に関する大人向けのこの作品
they have put education
彼らは教育を施してきた
Inclusion of adult education
成人教育の導入
A concept of health care
ヘルスケアの概念
This is the concept of health care
これがヘルスケアの考え方です
Force the elderly to study as much as possible
高齢者に可能な限り勉強を強制する
Prevent brain degeneration from affecting body degeneration
脳の変性が体の変性に影響を与えるのを防ぐ
Then this is hope
それならこれは希望だ
If Mr. Su says there is a chance
スーさんが言うならチャンスはある
Introduce this concept to our Taiwan
この概念を私たちの台湾に導入してください
lest in the next ten years there will be old people crawling everywhere
今後10年以内に、どこにでも這う老人がいるだろうから
The second situation is that
2つ目の状況は、
Just now I mentioned this so-called prevention
先ほど、いわゆる予防について触れました。
The United States is now in
米国は現在、
There is a building next to the old house
古い家の隣に建物があります
There is an old house next to the Jiansheng house
建生家の隣に古い家があります
they are now in person
彼らは今、直接会っています
intimate self
親密な自分
Already did bad things
すでに悪いことをした
But our teacher in Taiwan said
でも台湾の先生はこう言いました。
I often participate in private
プライベートでもよく参加します
Private students learn many activities
私立学生は多くのアクティビティを学びます
Or Teacher Wang Peiling
または王培林先生
often have some activities
何らかの活動をすることが多い
I will send my DM
DMを送ります
As a result, the students did not show up
結果的に生徒たちは来なかった
The idea of ​​brain degeneration
脳の変性という考え方
Hope it might be
そうかもしれないと願っています
Take a little effort to promote
少し頑張って宣伝してみよう
lest it be said that the burden will be heavier
負担が大きくなると言われないように
Caused by degeneration of the brain
脳の変性が原因
Degeneration of the body thank you
体の変性、ありがとう
Thanks
ありがとう
As for
はどうかと言うと
cerebral
脳の
rehabilitation for this memory
この記憶のリハビリテーション
I think
私が思うに
Of course it's not me
もちろん私ではありません
I am professional
私はプロフェッショナルです
i thought i would ask more
もっと聞いてみようと思った
the expert
専門家
then think again
それからもう一度考えてください
see how to do it in this direction
この方向でそれを行う方法を参照してください
Thanks
ありがとう
Su Chang, I think my question may not have a direct concept with what you just said
スー・チャン、私の質問はあなたの今言ったことと直接の概念が無いかもしれません。
But you're an expert on old founders
でもあなたは古い創業者についての専門家です
I also want to hear your opinion
あなたの意見も聞きたいです
We often see reports abroad
海外での報道もよく見かけますが、
Some people wake up suddenly after being in a coma for many years
長年昏睡状態にあった後に突然目覚める人もいる
What is the reason for being sober?
地味な理由は何ですか？
The other is that these people, after waking up,
もう一つは、この人たちは目覚めた後、
Has his brain function fully recovered?
脳機能は完全に回復したのでしょうか？
Or because a certain part will definitely suffer some damage
または、特定の部分が何らかの損傷を受ける必要があるため
yes thank you
はい、ありがとうございます
in my experience
私の経験では
In fact, quite a few recovered
実際、かなりの数が回復しました
Even some hypoxic patients
一部の低酸素患者でも
Well, after half a year and a year, he's fine again.
半年後、1年後、彼はまた元気になりました。
But the barriers to function are huge
しかし、機能への障壁は非常に大きい
Some hands and feet are not good
一部の手と足がダメです
But some hands and feet are good but he has almost no memory
でも、手足の一部は大丈夫ですが、記憶がほとんどありません。
Well, it's better. I've seen it too.
まあ、そのほうがいいですね。私も見ました。
There is a patient who wakes up six months a year
1年に半年も目覚める患者がいる
And there are no obstacles
そして障害物は何もない
Of course, I think this is mostly a reward function.
もちろん、これは主に報酬関数だと思います。
less likely to regenerate
再生する可能性が低い
then this is a
それならこれは
I'm a photo studio
私は写真スタジオです
I have been around for so long, I have only experienced one year and six months
長く生きてきて、まだ1年6ヶ月しか経験していないのですが、
A child in a photo studio
写真スタジオにいる子供
a couple
一個夫婦
take good care of this kid
この子の世話をよくしてください
every day is like
毎日がこんな感じ
I'll tell a story by the way
ところで話をします
this
これ
A good man talks to him every day like this
いい男は毎日こうやって話しかける
how about him
彼についてはどうですか
take care of him fearlessly
恐れることなく彼の世話をする
Every day every two weeks for three weeks
2週間ごとに3週間毎日
Or look at taking medicine or something like that
あるいは薬の服用などを検討してください
Then I remember he told me
それから彼が私に言ったのを覚えています
When he woke up at twenty-four
彼が二十四時に起きたとき
after waking up
起きた後
It's getting better and better in a few days
数日でどんどん良くなっていきます
he asked him
彼は彼に尋ねた
Back of CAM
CAM裏
That's the one
それだ
Call that CAM again
その CAM を再度呼び出します
It seems to be from 2008, I will talk about it later
2008年のもののようですが、それについては後で話します
It was expensive when he saw it. At that time, it was tens of thousands of 1.6 million
見たときはとても高価で、当時は160万～数万でした。
He seems to have about 800,000 yuan left after he wakes up
目が覚めると80万元くらい残っているらしい
so he told me the story
それで彼は私にその話をしてくれました
There are not many such examples
そんな例はあまりない
No symptoms can be seen like recovered skin
皮膚の回復などの症状は見られません
But most of the time there will be partial recovery of function
しかし、ほとんどの場合、機能は部分的に回復します。
And it will leave some legacy
そして残り物も増えるだろう
I don't know what kind of patients Director Jiang has encountered.
江院長がどのような患者に出会ってきたのかは分からない。
There are still cases where the patient wakes up for a long time
患者が長時間覚醒するケースも依然としてある
Usually people are everywhere
通常、どこにでも人がいます
But after waking up
でも、起きてからは
No matter how well his brain functions, it can be explained.
彼の脳がどれほど機能しているとしても、それは説明できます。
In fact the whole brain functions like a specialty kyogen
実は脳全体が専門の狂言のように機能している
It means that every member of the troupe must sing well
それは、劇団のメンバー全員が上手に歌わなければならないことを意味します
So we're honestly a whole function
つまり、正直に言うと、私たちは完全な関数です
So when our honestly functioning cells
ですから、私たちの細胞が誠実に機能するとき、
More often it is our husband's chance
多くの場合、それは夫のチャンスです
When missing basically his
基本的に彼がいなくなったとき
He may look like you can see through
彼はあなたから見透かされているように見えるかもしれません
when you give him some tests
彼にいくつかのテストを与えるとき
also found that we can't do it
それができないこともわかった
The most common is memory
最も一般的なのは記憶です
just tell him this
彼にこれを伝えてください
had breakfast
朝食を食べた
Special finished his lunch with two breakfasts once
スペシャルは 2 回の朝食を 1 回で昼食を終えました
He can't afford it every season
彼には毎シーズンそれを買う余裕はない
I have to remember the memory that exists or give me a season
存在する記憶を思い出さないと 季節を与えられない
probably like this memory
おそらくこの思い出が好きでしょう
That is to say, his husband can't
つまり夫はそれができない
I can't keep up with everything for you
私はあなたのすべてに追いつくことができません
Thanks
ありがとう
now purser sorry
さてパーサーごめんなさい
because I'm sorry I didn't see you that
見れなくてごめんなさいだから
2007 should come
2007年が来るはずだ
then i was thinking
それから私は考えていました
How long is the best time for this patient to arrive at the hospital
この患者が病院に到着するのにどれくらいの時間が最適ですか
to be sent to the hospital
病院に送られる
that future
その未来
future words
未来の言葉
i won't please
お願いしません
Of course it is the biggest job outside of God
もちろんそれは神の外での最大の仕事です
But in the future, can the beef be regenerated?
しかし、将来的に牛肉は再生できるのでしょうか？
Or is there some drug that can regenerate it
それとも再生させる薬があるのでしょうか？
Because the whole thing looks like a neuropathy
全部神経障害っぽいから
It should be that symptom, probably a beef problem.
それはその症状のはずで、おそらく牛肉の問題です。
Is there any better medicine?
もっと良い薬はありますか？
at present
現在のところ
So far there has been no major breakthrough
これまでのところ大きな進歩はありません
Including Stem Cells
幹細胞を含む
someone put it in the brain
誰かが脳にそれを入れた
How about it
どうでしょうか
haven't had a big breakthrough yet.
まだ大きな進歩を遂げていない
But there are constant heart medicine coming out
しかし、心臓病の薬は次々と出てきます
That is to help some metabolism
それは代謝を助けるためです
or how
あるいはどうやって
But the real regeneration is not so much
しかし、本当の再生はそれほどではありません
This still has to work hard
これはまだ頑張らなければなりません
Stem Cell is in the animal seems to have some help
幹細胞は動物の中にあり、何らかの助けになるようです
But if you really use it on people
でも本当に人に対して使うなら
not necessarily
必ずしも
This is too complicated
これは複雑すぎます
Environmental factors have too much influence
環境要因の影響が大きすぎる
Yes, this practice certainly has
はい、この実践には確かに効果があります
But everyone always try their best
でもみんないつも全力で頑張ってます
Really see regeneration in people
人々の再生を実際に見る
not too that
それほどでもない
Thanks
ありがとう
Yoon-hyun and then sell the two girls, please.
ユンヒョン、それでは二人の女の子を売ってください。
I would like to ask, that is usually after our limbs are severed
聞きたいのですが、それはたいてい手足を切断された後です
If you want to untie it back, what can't you do after your brain is broken?
それをほどきたいなら、脳が壊れてしまったらどうすることもできないでしょうか？
Then I want to ask, that is, assuming that our brain
そこで聞きたいのですが、つまり、私たちの脳が
That is, a certain part, for example, was cut off
たとえば、ある部分が切り取られたことを意味します。
It's the part of the brain that's been cut off.
切り取られた脳の一部です。
Then what will its original function be?
では、本来の機能は何になるのでしょうか？
It's the one we were talking about
それは私たちが話していたものです
Is there any connectivity? This place we sometimes
接続はありますか? この場所は時々私たちが行きます
During the operation, the pressure on the brain was too high, the dry breath just mentioned
手術中、脳への圧力が高すぎて、先ほど述べた息が乾いていました。
dry mask
ドライマスク
When you squeeze me out, there is no way to eliminate some of the less important places
あなたが私を締め出すとき、重要でない場所のいくつかを取り除く方法はありません
This karma will also erase it
このカルマも消してくれる
Where does it go after disappearing?
消えた後はどこへ行くのでしょうか？
run to the other side run to other places
向こう側へ走ってください 別の場所へ走ってください
it comes with a reward
それは報酬が付属しています
A lot of the brain's function is to help that person live in other places.
脳の機能の多くは、その人が他の場所で生きていくのを助けることです。
Just like the choir he mentioned here
彼がここで言及した合唱団のように
That white gull token is broken
その白カモメトークンは壊れています
in the end please go on
最後に続けてください
Of course, the function is not as good as before
もちろん機能は以前ほどではありません
But what about this
しかし、これはどうでしょうか
it always brings rewards
それは常に報酬をもたらします
no way
とんでもない
There is no way to connect the Sino-Soviet nerve until now
今のところ中ソの神経を繋ぐ方法はない
studied for a long time
長い間勉強した
if this can be regenerated
これが再生できれば
become the Norbert winner
ノーバートの勝者になる
This problem is the Sino-Soviet nerve
この問題は中ソ神経の問題だ
it is mainly missing a
主に欠けているのは
Original Dental Site
オリジナル歯科サイト
then what
じゃあ何
do not know
わかりません
i forgot now
今は忘れました
probably so far
おそらくこれまでのところ
There is no way for the central nervous system
中枢神経系には仕方が無い
Regenerate
再生的
But when he gets around, he can
しかし、彼が立ち回れば、それができる
He can regenerate after denervation
神経除去後も再生できる
The question is, the lady in front
質問は、目の前の女性です。
Thanks
ありがとう
Director thank you for protecting young people
監督、若者を守ってくれてありがとう
Afterwards I was just listening to the director strict barrier
その後、私はただ厳格な障壁の監督の話を聞いていました
There are references to the brain
脳に関する言及があります
Part of the biomarker
バイオマーカーの一部
i feel very interested
とても興味があると感じます
so i want to know say
だから私は知りたいです、言う
Can biomarkers become
バイオマーカーはなれるのか
Determining patients with cerebral arterial flow
脳動脈血流のある患者の判定
An indicator of the need for surgery
手術の必要性を示す指標
good question
良い質問
Cerebral arterial flow is like this
脳動脈の流れはこんな感じ
If cerebral arterial flow is usually
脳動脈の流れが正常であれば、
It doesn't have to be broken before everyone will show symptoms.
誰もが症状を示す前に、それが壊れる必要はありません。
What about some that you are talking about are not broken?
あなたが話している壊れていないものについてはどうですか?
suddenly discovered
突然発見された
Then probably quite a high percentage have found this
おそらくかなりの割合でこれを見つけたでしょう
about a few percent
数パーセントくらい
one to three or so
1つから3つくらい
Sometimes this arterial flow is found in routine examinations
この動脈血流は定期検査で見つかることがあります。
Then do you want to go under the knife?
それならナイフの下に潜り込みたいですか？
some smaller
もう少し小さい
sometimes or never broken
時々壊れたり、壊れたりしない
or in a more dangerous place
あるいはもっと危険な場所に
Sometimes we don't advocate surgery
手術を推奨しない場合もあります
Well BioMarker has no way of knowing that
まあ、BioMarker にはそれを知る方法がありません
Because generally unless that arterial flow has been pressed to some brain
なぜなら、動脈の流れが脳のどこかに押し付けられていない限り、一般的には
The brain releases abnormal markers due to injury
脳は損傷により異常なマーカーを放出します
He just needs to go under the knife
彼はナイフの下に行くだけでいいのです
Only then did I know if he was under pressure and the pressure was crushed to the brain
そのとき初めて、彼がプレッシャーを受けていて、そのプレッシャーが脳を圧迫していたかどうかが分かりました。
If it's very small arterial flow probably not
動脈血流量が非常に少ない場合はおそらくそうではありません
not easy to find
見つけるのは簡単ではありません
that if big
それが大きかったら
he can see
彼は見える
I think
私が思うに
The development of BioMaker is
BioMakerの開発は、
a hope for the future
未来への希望
so probably
だからおそらく
Many people are looking for this thing now
今これを探している人がたくさんいます
See if you can actually do some
実際にいくつかのことができるかどうかを確認してください
that's like this brigade lake
それはこの旅団の湖のようなものです
average travel lake
平均的な旅行湖
Do you know what arterial flow means?
動脈血流の意味を知っていますか？
arterial flow is not flow
動脈流不是流
arterial flow is a
動脈の流れは
where the blood vessels cross
血管が交差する場所
there is a weakness here
ここに弱点があります
it sticks out
それは突き出ています
highlight a little
少しハイライトする
But at the age of
しかし、その年齢では、
it breaks
壊れる
Broken brain hemorrhage
壊れた脳出血
can't save
保存できません
or
また
go in and clip it off
中に入って切り取ってください
cut it off
それを切り取る
that some arterial flow
何らかの動脈の流れ
before it broke
壊れる前に
It's on a routine MRI
定期的なMRI検査です
Or CT scan found
またはCTスキャンで見つかった
that's what we just did
それが私たちがたった今やったことです
This is located in the proposed
これは提案された場所にあります
made by miss
ミスが作った
Are you going to clamp it off?
締め切るつもりですか？
very
とても
fee this
これに料金を支払う
Dime gold
ダイムゴールド
This is for clinical use
これは臨床用です
Probably Meyermag didn't help on this one
おそらくマイヤーマグはこれについては役に立たなかったでしょう
I'm sorry, may I ask Su Chang
すみません、スー・チャンに聞いてもいいですか
If say after your brain contusion
脳挫傷の後だとしたら
after surgery
手術後
A piece of your skull is missing
頭蓋骨の一部が欠けている
Will that affect the whole
それは全体に影響しますか
Won't
しません
Will he
彼はするだろうか
His brain injury is more important
彼の脳損傷の方が重要だ
Brain injury is more important
脳損傷の方が重要だ
Will it affect your optic nerve?
視神経に影響はありますか？
optic nerve
視神経
that depends on the location
それは場所によります
If the optic nerve goes this way
視神経がこの方向を通ると
If you are affecting sometimes
時々影響を及ぼしている場合
will affect
影響するだろう
some people will affect
影響を受ける人もいるだろう
look at the location
場所を見てください
What if it affects the future?
それが将来に影響を与えたらどうなるでしょうか？
what will happen
何が起こるか
Okay, let me talk about the bones first.
さて、最初に骨について話しましょう。
bone
骨
bone defect
骨欠損
often see
よく見る
because for the time
なぜならその時のために
I was talking about the dry bread just now
さっき乾パンの話をしてたんだけど
squeezed out
絞り出された
So when you need to save your life
したがって、自分の命を救う必要があるときは、
put the bones
骨を入れる
let go of the bones
骨を手放す
put it up
それを上げてください
that's okay
大丈夫
It will collapse badly for patients in the future
将来的には患者にとってひどく崩壊するだろう
You can even raise a bird here
ここでは鳥を育てることもできる
so big
とても大きく
but it won't happen
でもそれは起こらない
will not affect the patient
患者には影響しません
That's progress now
それはもう進歩です
Now it is even possible to use a computer to defend
今ではコンピュータを使って防御することも可能です
Do this arc and everything well
このアークとすべてをうまくやってください
and then put it in
そしてそれを入れます
Dress up exactly like you used to
以前とまったく同じようにドレスアップしてください
Of course it's best if your own bones are the best
もちろん自分の骨が一番良いに越したことはありませんが、
But now it can be done well
でも今なら上手にできるよ
so don't worry about this
だから心配しないでください
What about your second question?
2番目の質問はどうでしょうか？
I suddenly can't think
急に考えられなくなった
Will it affect the four nerves?
4つの神経に影響を与えるのでしょうか？
maybe a nerve
たぶん神経質
Yes, this is the position where you will be injured.
はい、ここは怪我をする位置です。
facial nerve words
顔面神経の言葉
Sometimes the path of its facial nerve is injured
顔面神経の通り道が損傷されることもあります
That face is crooked
その顔は歪んでいる
Then the four nerve pathways will be crooked if injured.
そして、損傷すると4つの神経経路が曲がってしまいます。
also can't see
も見えない
So it all depends on the location of the injury.
したがって、すべては怪我の場所によって異なります。
What if it only affects
影響するだけだったらどうしよう
affected
影響を受ける
For example, let's see why
たとえば、その理由を見てみましょう
The facial nerve because it is not the Sino-Soviet nerve
顔面神経は中ソ神経ではないので
So some can be used
したがって、いくつかは接続できます
but very difficult
でもとても難しい
The regeneration rate is not necessarily high
必ずしも回復率が高いわけではない
Four nerves are more difficult
四神経はもっと難しい
Four nerves if it is because
神経が4本あるからだと
Fractures compress this to sometimes decompress it from the bone
骨折によりこれが圧縮され、場合によっては骨から減圧されます。
it recovers some
いくらか回復する
in place of the four nerve tubes
4本の神経管の代わりに
Often there will be a fracture in this place that presses it
この場所を圧迫する骨折がよくあります
there is hope for that
希望がある
But it may not be able to recover much
でもあまり回復できないかもしれない
here's a question leave
ここで質問があります
hello secretary
こんにちは、秘書
I now have a medical
今は診察を受けています
I want to ask you about the actual case
実際のケースについてお聞きしたいのですが
OK
OK
The first is to say
一つ目は言うことです
In October 1999
1999年10月
that is
あれは
Four knots when driving
走行時は4ノット
One car becomes two or three
1台の車が2台、3台になる
Later, I went to take a radiography
この後、レントゲンを撮りに行きました
Underwater tumors found under the brain
脳の下に水中腫瘍が見つかる
Later, it was surgery with a small Weijing pen gun.
その後、小型の魏京ペン銃による手術となった。
had surgery
手術を受けた
Hospitalized for about ten days
10日ほど入院
It's been almost a year and a half now
もう1年半近く経ちます
Follow up every six months
半年ごとにフォローアップする
Now tracking and found another problem is in
現在追跡中、別の問題が見つかった
Where the blood vessels grow again
血管が再び成長する場所
but after outpatient
しかし外来後
It's now going to be treated with a type of radiation
これから放射線治療が行われる予定です
because in the blood vessels
血管の中だから
there's no way to do it again
もう一度やる方法はありません
This symptom is what the director just mentioned
この症状は先ほど院長がおっしゃったものです
just dizzy
ただめまいがする
headaches sleep disturbances energy disturbances
頭痛 睡眠障害 エネルギー障害
There is one more serious
もう一つ深刻なことがあります
emotionally unstable
情緒不安定
a good day a bad day
良い日、悪い日
Now if the machine tracks
さて、機械が追跡するなら
It uses a method called radiation
放射性物質を使用しているので、
radiation therapy
放射治療
Radiation therapy I further understand is to use
放射線療法を使用する必要があると私はさらに理解しています
Noni knife
ノニナイフ
It's right to treat with a Noni knife
ノニナイフを使って治療するのが正しい
Then I want to ask the Commissioner
そこで長官にお聞きしたいのですが
This noni knife treatment will have
このノニナイフトリートメントでは、
What are the side effects?
副作用は何ですか
Thanks
ありがとう
By the way, let me tell you about the pituitary gland
ところで、脳下垂体についてお話します。
The pituitary gland flow is quite special
下垂体の流れは非常に特殊です
it grows in the center of the brain
脳の中心で成長します
pituitary fossa
下垂体窩
grow out of that
そこから成長する
grow one
一つ成長する
The biggest one is that it affects just
最も大きなものは、次のような影響を与えるということです。
it's just under that forty gold cross
それはその40ゴールドクロスのすぐ下にあります
so when it gets up
それで起きたら
The first one goes to the top of the four-cross
最初のものはフォークロスのトップに行きます
what would a quadruple cross cause
4重十字は何を引き起こすでしょうか
two sided horses
両面馬
Now suddenly you feel that this person often has this
今、あなたは突然、この人はよくこんなことをしていると感じます。
I wonder why this person suddenly became so proud
この人はどうして急に偉そうになったんだろう
I'm not happy with this big hello
この盛大な挨拶には満足していない
Because he can't see clearly on either side of the outside.
なぜなら、外側のどちら側もはっきりと見えないからです。
so sometimes you don't know you're driving
だから時々、自分が運転していることに気づかないことがある
easy to change pressure to get
取得する圧力を簡単に変更できます
Someone gets you on the walk and you don't even know
誰かがあなたを散歩に連れて行ってくれるのに、あなたはそれを知りません
So when you walk, you will meet this edge
だから歩くとこの端に出会うだろう
because he can't see
彼は目が見えないから
So he pressed from the optic chiasm
そこで彼は視交叉から圧迫した
so he will
だから彼はそうするだろう
So after the surgery
それで手術後は
He's such a cute question
とても可愛い質問ですね
I think your symptoms should be fine.
あなたの症状は大丈夫だと思います。
Those who are cute are good
可愛い人は良いよ
is very stable now
今はとても安定しています
but he said it makes sense
しかし彼はそれは理にかなっていると言いました
I know
知っている
This is because he might be on the alarm cat
これは彼が目覚まし猫に乗っている可能性があるためです
stick on it
それに固執する
It is risky to stick to it and then take it
それに固執してからそれを取るのは危険です
use that noni knife
そのノニナイフを使ってください
We call it radiosurgery
私たちはそれを放射線手術と呼んでいます
It is different from radiation therapy
放射線治療とは違います
Radiation therapy is just radiation that
放射線療法はあくまでも放射線です。
The radiology surgery is inside the computer.
放射線科の手術はコンピューターの中にあります。
it's only a little bit
それはほんの少しです
but it's pretty accurate
しかしそれはかなり正確です
It turns front and back, left and right
前後左右に回転します
Any distance can be calculated
あらゆる距離を計算可能
it follows that place
それはその場所に続きます
all the light is concentrated there
すべての光がそこに集中する
burn that bit
そのビットを燃やしてください
what about this
これはどうですか
It's like putting that point
その点を置くようなものです
destroy the whole
全体を破壊する
brain damage
脳損傷
But it has little chance of injuring surrounding tissue
しかし、周囲の組織を傷つける可能性はほとんどありません
But there are also a few
でもいくつかあります
so still
まだ
of course there is a chance
もちろんチャンスはあります
but rarely
しかしまれに
because it is very accurate
非常に正確なので
So I guess this way is right
だからこのやり方が正しいんだと思う
that if you open it again
それをもう一度開いたら
sometimes that
時々それ
What if the arteries lose blood?
動脈が失血したらどうなるでしょうか？
or how suddenly broke
または突然壊れた
That's dangerous too
それも危険だよ
I think the doctor was very right in judging
医師の判断は非常に正しかったと思います
Come, Director Liang
さあ、リャン監督
I think because of time
時間のせいだと思う
probably the last question
おそらく最後の質問
OK
OK
OK I want to ask a fact
OK、事実を聞きたいのですが
It's a practical question
とても実践的な質問です
Although the dean Cheng Wu just said that
成武学部長がさっき言ったけど
Director for promoting this
推進ディレクター
relationship with security
セキュリティとの関係
Saved 3,000 lives a year
年間 3,000 人の命を救った
but in fact
しかし実際には
This affects other
これは他のものに影響を与えます
The Business of a Brain Surgeon
脳外科医の仕事
so i want to ask
それで聞きたいです
have you ever been scolded or
叱られたことがありますか、または
I was surprised to say
と言ってびっくりしました
we used to be surgeons
私たちはかつて外科医でした
everyone is very loving
みんなとても愛情深いです
so i was surprised
それで私は驚きました
When it was promoted in Taipei City for the first time
初めて台北市で宣伝したとき
Ward suddenly reduced by one-third
区は突然3分の1減らされた
I don't see anyone complaining
文句を言う人はいない
when the second push
2回目のプッシュのとき
that's even worse
それはさらに悪いことです
Because like many young physicians
なぜなら、多くの若い医師と同じように、
It's all based on this night
すべてはこの夜に基づいている
life in these emergency rooms
緊急治療室での生活
suddenly gone
突然いなくなった
It suddenly disappeared. It turned out to be a five-day knife in a week.
それが突然消えてしまい、一週間で五日分のナイフになってしまったのです。
less than one a week
週に1回未満
Taipei City in particular fell very fast
特に台北市は急速に崩壊した
But everyone is very used to it and thinks that saying this
でもみんな慣れていて、こんなことを言うのは気が引ける。
Including me, I don't think anyone opens these, and if it's safe to scold my brother, no one should open them
私を含めて、これを開ける人はいないと思います。弟を叱っても大丈夫なら、誰も開けるべきではありません
But he just can't do it like this, so fortunately no one complained, but a group complained
でも彼にはこのようにはできないので、幸いなことに誰も文句を言わなかったが、あるグループが文句を言った
keep learning, keep learning
学び続ける、学び続ける
No, all of a sudden, there were five or six hundred in a month, and suddenly there were two or three hundred left
いや、ある月に突然 500 か 600 になったのに、突然 200 か 300 が残った
less car accidents
交通事故が減る
This is another discovery, that
これはもう一つの発見です、
God's other star, no one complains
神のもう一つの星、誰も文句を言わない
i admire them
私は彼らを尊敬します
Thanks
ありがとう
I'm here to thank you very very much
とても感謝するためにここに来ました
Thank you very much Director
監督さん、本当にありがとうございました
If it wasn't for the director
監督がいなかったら
you advocate hard hats
あなたはヘルメットを支持します
I could maybe 10 years ago
10年前ならできたかも
I will become a professional
私はプロになります
really thank you very much
本当にありがとう
I think the director is blessed
監督は恵まれてると思う
all taxi groups
すべてのタクシーグループ
Thanks
ありがとう
our speech today
今日の私たちのスピーチ
come to apply
申し込みに来てください
this time we
今回は私たち
Thank you Director for giving us a new speech
局長、新たなスピーチをしていただきありがとうございました
Thank you also for the people
人々にも感謝します
Contribution of working with him
彼との協力による貢献